<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<quiz>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text><![CDATA[A binary liquid–vapour system at]]></text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[A binary liquid–vapour system at fixed pressure shows an azeotropic point in the \(T\)-\(x\) diagram. Considering Gibbs phase rule and the defining condition of an azeotrope, which statement best describes the degrees of freedom at the azeotropic point (at fixed \(P\))?]]></text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[In a binary two-phase (L+V) region at fixed pressure, the reduced phase rule gives \(F' = C - P + 1 = 2-2+1=1\), so normally one variable (e.g., \(T\)) can be varied and the equilibrium compositions adjust.
At an azeotrope there is an additional constraint: liquid and vapour compositions are identical (a singular point in the \(T\)-\(x\) diagram), which removes that remaining freedom, making the azeotropic state effectively invariant at that pressure.
Why others are wrong: Claiming one or two degrees of freedom ignores the extra azeotropic constraint; stating it is “not special” contradicts the text’s emphasis that the azeotrope appears as a singular point and imposes a distillation limitation.]]></text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[One intensive variable can be changed independently while retaining two phases and azeotropic condition.]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[No intensive variable can be changed independently while retaining two phases and azeotropic condition.]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Correct!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Two intensive variables can be changed independently while retaining two phases and azeotropic condition.]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Degrees of freedom is the same everywhere in the two-phase region, so the azeotropic point is not special.]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text><![CDATA[In a one-component \(P\)–\(T\) diagram]]></text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[In a one-component \(P\)–\(T\) diagram, the liquid–vapour equilibrium curve terminates at a critical point. Using phase-rule reasoning, which statement is the most accurate about how degrees of freedom changes when moving from (i) a two-phase point on the liquid–vapour curve to (ii) the critical point?]]></text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[For a one-component system, Gibbs phase rule is \(F=C-P+2\).
On a liquid–vapour coexistence curve, \(C=1\), \(P=2\) so \(F=1\); at the critical point the distinction between liquid and vapour disappears, effectively yielding a single phase (\(P=1\)) and thus \(F=2\), consistent with being able to vary \(T\) and \(P\) within a one-phase region.
Why others are wrong: Treating the critical point like a triple point (invariant) is incorrect; also, the critical point is not a generic two-phase boundary point because the two phases become indistinguishable there.]]></text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[\(F\) changes from 0 to 1 because two phases become one phase at the critical point.]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[\(F\) remains 1 at both locations because both still lie on a phase boundary.]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[\(F\) changes from 1 on the coexistence curve to 2 at the critical point because it becomes a single-phase region endpoint.]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Correct!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[\(F\) changes from 2 to 1 because a critical point is an invariant point like a triple point.]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text><![CDATA[A binary liquid–liquid system shows]]></text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[A binary liquid–liquid system shows a UCST with a consolute point. At a temperature slightly below UCST, a mixture splits into two liquid phases with compositions given by the ends of a tie line. Which statement correctly links the lever rule to the binodal/tie-line picture?]]></text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[In partially miscible liquid–liquid systems, the two-phase region is bounded by the binodal curve, and tie lines connect compositions of the two coexisting liquid phases at a given temperature.
The lever rule is explicitly used in liquid–liquid phase diagrams (as in the learning path) to determine relative phase amounts from the overall composition’s position along the tie line.
Why others are wrong: The lever rule is not restricted to eutectics; it applies wherever two phases coexist and a tie line can be drawn; the consolute point is where tie lines shrink to zero length, not where they uniquely exist.]]></text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[The lever rule applies only to solid–liquid eutectic diagrams, not to liquid–liquid diagrams.]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[The overall composition must lie outside the binodal for the lever rule to be used.]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[The overall composition lies on the tie line connecting the two coexisting compositions, and phase amounts are inversely proportional to the segment lengths.]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Correct!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Tie lines exist only at the consolute point, so lever rule can be applied only at UCST.]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text><![CDATA[Consider a binary solid–liquid phase]]></text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Consider a binary solid–liquid phase diagram where an intermediate compound forms and undergoes incongruent melting (peritectic reaction). Which qualitative statement is most consistent with “incongruent melting” in such diagrams?]]></text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[The syllabus explicitly distinguishes congruent vs. incongruent melting as different solid-phase behaviors during melting in two-component systems.
Incongruent melting means the solid does not melt to a liquid of the same composition; instead it participates in a reaction (often peritectic) producing a liquid and another solid of different composition.
Why others are wrong: “Same composition liquid” defines congruent melting; “liquid and vapour identical” describes azeotropy (liquid–vapour), not melting; complete solid miscibility refers to solid solutions, not incongruent melting behavior.]]></text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[The solid melts to a liquid of the same composition as the solid at a single temperature.]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[On heating, the solid decomposes to a liquid plus a different solid phase rather than producing a liquid of identical composition.]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Correct!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[The liquid and vapour compositions become identical at the melting point.]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[The solid becomes completely miscible with the other solid phase at all temperatures.]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text><![CDATA[A distillation column is used]]></text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[A distillation column is used for a binary mixture that forms an azeotrope at the operating pressure. Which statement best captures why increasing the number of equilibrium stages (theoretical plates) alone cannot yield a product composition beyond the azeotrope?]]></text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Fractional distillation relies on vapour–liquid equilibrium giving a vapour composition different from the liquid composition (enrichment driven by differential volatility).
At an azeotrope, the liquid and vapour compositions are identical, so the driving force for separation vanishes and adding more equilibrium stages cannot cross that composition limit at the same pressure.
Why others are wrong: Triple point and eutectic are different equilibria (one-component three-phase; binary solid–liquid invariant) and do not explain distillation limits; the phase rule allows two phases in binary systems at constant pressure and is routinely used for such diagrams.
(https://ppl-ai-file-upload.s3.amazonaws.com/web/direct-files/collection_99e4096c-742b-4ed1-9fa1-79a24cd1a07e/c8559d0f-a3ee-4a44-bd03-d515f36af380/physical_unit_07.txt)]]></text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Because at the azeotrope the system is at a triple point.]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Because at the azeotrope the relative volatility effectively becomes 1 since liquid and vapour compositions are identical.]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Correct!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Because the phase rule forbids two phases in binary systems at constant pressure.]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Because the azeotrope corresponds to a eutectic point that blocks vapour formation.]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
</quiz>
