<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<quiz>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text><![CDATA[An atomic transition is labeled]]></text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[An atomic transition is labeled “electric-dipole forbidden” in the LS-coupling picture. Which statement best explains why such a line can still be experimentally observed (though weak) in real spectra?]]></text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[In quantum mechanics, “forbidden” typically means the transition dipole moment (transition moment integral) is zero under an idealized symmetry/coupling approximation, giving vanishing intensity in that approximation.  Real atoms/molecules deviate from the idealized limit because interactions such as spin–orbit coupling and configuration mixing perturb the eigenstates, so the initially forbidden transition can borrow intensity from allowed transitions and become weakly observable.  Temperature and Doppler effects influence populations and linewidths, not the fundamental dipole-allowed/forbidden character, and energy conservation is never violated by a genuine spectral line.]]></text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Selection rules are exact only if the transition moment integral is strictly zero; small state-mixing (e.g., spin–orbit, configuration interaction) can make the transition moment nonzero]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Correct!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Forbidden transitions become allowed only at absolute zero temperature]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Forbidden transitions become strong when Doppler broadening dominates]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Forbidden transitions violate energy conservation, so observed lines must be artifacts]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text><![CDATA[In terms of the transition]]></text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[In terms of the transition moment integral, the most fundamental criterion for an electric dipole transition between two stationary states \(\psi_i\) and \(\psi_f\) to be allowed is that:]]></text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Electric-dipole selection rules are compactly expressed through the transition dipole moment integral; if its symmetry makes it vanish, the transition intensity is (ideally) zero and the line is “forbidden.”  This symmetry-based viewpoint connects directly to group theory language: the transition moment function must contain the totally symmetric representation for the integral to be nonzero.  Equal energies are irrelevant to allowedness (they would imply no photon energy), and commutation of \(\hat{\mu}\) with the Hamiltonian is not the criterion for radiative transition probability.]]></text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[\(\int \psi_f^* \,\hat{\mu}\, \psi_i \, d\tau \neq 0\) (i.e., the transition moment is nonzero)]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Correct!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[\(\int \psi_f^* \,\hat{\mu}\, \psi_i \, d\tau = 0\)]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[\(\psi_f\) and \(\psi_i\) must have the same energy]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[\(\hat{\mu}\) must commute with the Hamiltonian]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text><![CDATA[A measured isolated spectral line]]></text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[A measured isolated spectral line is well-fit by a Voigt profile. The most consistent physical interpretation is that the observed line shape arises from:]]></text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[In spectroscopy, Gaussian profiles are typically associated with Doppler broadening from thermal velocity distributions, while Lorentzian profiles are associated with lifetime (natural) and collisional (pressure) broadening.  When both broadening classes contribute significantly, the resulting profile is the convolution of the two, called a Voigt profile.  Purely Doppler or purely lifetime broadening would not generally require a Voigt description, and instrumental broadening can contribute but does not uniquely imply a Voigt form without underlying physical mechanisms.]]></text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Convolution of a Gaussian mechanism (e.g., Doppler) with a Lorentzian mechanism (e.g., natural/pressure broadening)]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Correct!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Purely Doppler broadening with no collisional or lifetime effects]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Purely lifetime broadening with zero thermal motion]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Instrumental broadening only, with no physical broadening]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text><![CDATA[In a UV-Vis absorption spectrum]]></text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[In a UV-Vis absorption spectrum, two transitions have the same transition energy, but one band has much larger molar extinction coefficient \(\varepsilon\). The best quantum-mechanical reason is that the stronger band has:]]></text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[The intensity of an electronic absorption is governed by the transition probability, which is directly tied to the transition dipole moment (transition moment integral) and is commonly quantified via oscillator strength and experimentally via \(\varepsilon\).  If two transitions are at the same energy, the major differentiator for intensity is how strongly the radiation field couples the initial and final states, i.e., how large the transition dipole moment is (and thus how “allowed” the transition is).  Reduced mass and rotational constants are central to vibrational/rotational structure, and the external NMR field \(B_0\) is unrelated to UV-Vis band intensity.]]></text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[A larger magnitude of transition dipole moment (larger transition moment integral), hence larger oscillator strength]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Correct!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[A smaller reduced mass of the molecule]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[A larger rotational constant \(B\)]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[A smaller external magnetic field \(B_0\)]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text><![CDATA[A student claims: “If Doppler]]></text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[A student claims: “If Doppler broadening increases with temperature, then the integrated absorption area of a single isolated transition must also increase with temperature because the line gets wider.” Which statement most correctly evaluates this claim?]]></text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Line broadening mechanisms (Doppler, pressure, natural) primarily change the line shape and how intensity is distributed versus frequency, not automatically the total probability associated with the transition.  Increasing Doppler width with temperature commonly spreads absorption over a wider range, lowering the peak amplitude for the same overall transition strength, so “wider” does not imply “larger integrated area.”  Lorentzian vs Gaussian affects the functional form of the line, but the misconception remains: width alone does not dictate the integrated strength, and forbidden/allowed character affects baseline strength rather than the geometric conclusion about width versus area.
(https://ppl-ai-file-upload.s3.amazonaws.com/web/direct-files/collection_99e4096c-742b-4ed1-9fa1-79a24cd1a07e/065ae3cc-ba52-4a98-beb8-27f6d5393003/physical_unit_05.txt)
(https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Selection_rule)
(https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Voigt_profile)
(https://www.surfacesciencewestern.com/wp-content/uploads/ass18_biesinger.pdf)
(https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/fitting-spectral-lines-gaussian-versus-lorentzian-voigt-aulin)
(https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S0263224125012680)
(https://blog.truegeometry.com/calculators/Voigt_profile_calculation.html)
(https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Transition_dipole_moment)
(https://talk.q-chem.com/t/understanding-tddft-output-transition-moment-and-oscillator-strength/1734)
(https://heasarc.gsfc.nasa.gov/docs/software/xspec/manual/node247.html)
(https://entri.app/blog/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/selection-rules.pdf)
(https://alpha.chem.umb.edu/chemistry/ch612/documents/Week4.pdf)
(https://heasarc.gsfc.nasa.gov/docs/xanadu/xspec/manual/node243.html)
(https://talk.q-chem.com/t/oscillator-strength-formula/1766)
(https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S0169433218308766)
(https://bingweb.binghamton.edu/~suzuki/QuantumMechanicsFiles/2-2_Selection_rule_for_electric_dipole_transition.pdf)
(https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Oscillator_strength)
(https://scipython.com/books/book2/chapter-8-scipy/examples/the-voigt-profile/)
(https://chem.libretexts.org/Bookshelves/Physical_and_Theoretical_Chemistry_Textbook_Maps/Supplemental_Modules_(Physical_and_Theoretical_Chemistry)/Spectroscopy/Fundamentals_of_Spectroscopy/Selection_rules_and_transition_moment_integral)
(https://www.physik.fu-berlin.de/einrichtungen/ag/ag-heyne/docs/teaching/Advanced-Atomic-and-Molecular-Physics/abs_fl_calculations_en.pdf)
(https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Spectral_line_shape)]]></text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[The claim is incorrect: broadening redistributes intensity over frequency; width can increase while peak height decreases, and total area is not forced to increase just because the line is wider]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Correct!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[The claim is correct: wider lines always have larger integrated area]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[The claim is correct only for Lorentzian lines, not for Gaussian lines]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[The claim is correct only if the transition is electric-dipole forbidden]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
</quiz>
