<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<quiz>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text>A binary liquid–vapour system at</text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text>A binary liquid–vapour system at fixed pressure shows an azeotropic point in the \(T\)-\(x\) diagram. Considering Gibbs phase rule and the defining condition of an azeotrope, which statement best describes the degrees of freedom at the azeotropic point (at fixed \(P\))?</text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text>In a binary two-phase (L+V) region at fixed pressure, the reduced phase rule gives \(F' = C - P + 1 = 2-2+1=1\), so normally one variable (e.g., \(T\)) can be varied and the equilibrium compositions adjust.
At an azeotrope there is an additional constraint: liquid and vapour compositions are identical (a singular point in the \(T\)-\(x\) diagram), which removes that remaining freedom, making the azeotropic state effectively invariant at that pressure.
Why others are wrong: Claiming one or two degrees of freedom ignores the extra azeotropic constraint; stating it is “not special” contradicts the text’s emphasis that the azeotrope appears as a singular point and imposes a distillation limitation.</text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>One intensive variable can be changed independently while retaining two phases and azeotropic condition.</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text>No intensive variable can be changed independently while retaining two phases and azeotropic condition.</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Correct!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>Two intensive variables can be changed independently while retaining two phases and azeotropic condition.</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>Degrees of freedom is the same everywhere in the two-phase region, so the azeotropic point is not special.</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text>In a one-component \(P\)–\(T\) diagram</text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text>In a one-component \(P\)–\(T\) diagram, the liquid–vapour equilibrium curve terminates at a critical point. Using phase-rule reasoning, which statement is the most accurate about how degrees of freedom changes when moving from (i) a two-phase point on the liquid–vapour curve to (ii) the critical point?</text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text>For a one-component system, Gibbs phase rule is \(F=C-P+2\).
On a liquid–vapour coexistence curve, \(C=1\), \(P=2\) so \(F=1\); at the critical point the distinction between liquid and vapour disappears, effectively yielding a single phase (\(P=1\)) and thus \(F=2\), consistent with being able to vary \(T\) and \(P\) within a one-phase region.
Why others are wrong: Treating the critical point like a triple point (invariant) is incorrect; also, the critical point is not a generic two-phase boundary point because the two phases become indistinguishable there.</text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>\(F\) changes from 0 to 1 because two phases become one phase at the critical point.</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>\(F\) remains 1 at both locations because both still lie on a phase boundary.</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text>\(F\) changes from 1 on the coexistence curve to 2 at the critical point because it becomes a single-phase region endpoint.</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Correct!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>\(F\) changes from 2 to 1 because a critical point is an invariant point like a triple point.</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text>A binary liquid–liquid system shows</text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text>A binary liquid–liquid system shows a UCST with a consolute point. At a temperature slightly below UCST, a mixture splits into two liquid phases with compositions given by the ends of a tie line. Which statement correctly links the lever rule to the binodal/tie-line picture?</text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text>In partially miscible liquid–liquid systems, the two-phase region is bounded by the binodal curve, and tie lines connect compositions of the two coexisting liquid phases at a given temperature.
The lever rule is explicitly used in liquid–liquid phase diagrams (as in the learning path) to determine relative phase amounts from the overall composition’s position along the tie line.
Why others are wrong: The lever rule is not restricted to eutectics; it applies wherever two phases coexist and a tie line can be drawn; the consolute point is where tie lines shrink to zero length, not where they uniquely exist.</text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>The lever rule applies only to solid–liquid eutectic diagrams, not to liquid–liquid diagrams.</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>The overall composition must lie outside the binodal for the lever rule to be used.</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text>The overall composition lies on the tie line connecting the two coexisting compositions, and phase amounts are inversely proportional to the segment lengths.</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Correct!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>Tie lines exist only at the consolute point, so lever rule can be applied only at UCST.</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text>Consider a binary solid–liquid phase</text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text>Consider a binary solid–liquid phase diagram where an intermediate compound forms and undergoes incongruent melting (peritectic reaction). Which qualitative statement is most consistent with “incongruent melting” in such diagrams?</text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text>The syllabus explicitly distinguishes congruent vs. incongruent melting as different solid-phase behaviors during melting in two-component systems.
Incongruent melting means the solid does not melt to a liquid of the same composition; instead it participates in a reaction (often peritectic) producing a liquid and another solid of different composition.
Why others are wrong: “Same composition liquid” defines congruent melting; “liquid and vapour identical” describes azeotropy (liquid–vapour), not melting; complete solid miscibility refers to solid solutions, not incongruent melting behavior.</text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>The solid melts to a liquid of the same composition as the solid at a single temperature.</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text>On heating, the solid decomposes to a liquid plus a different solid phase rather than producing a liquid of identical composition.</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Correct!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>The liquid and vapour compositions become identical at the melting point.</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>The solid becomes completely miscible with the other solid phase at all temperatures.</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text>A distillation column is used</text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text>A distillation column is used for a binary mixture that forms an azeotrope at the operating pressure. Which statement best captures why increasing the number of equilibrium stages (theoretical plates) alone cannot yield a product composition beyond the azeotrope?</text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text>Fractional distillation relies on vapour–liquid equilibrium giving a vapour composition different from the liquid composition (enrichment driven by differential volatility).
At an azeotrope, the liquid and vapour compositions are identical, so the driving force for separation vanishes and adding more equilibrium stages cannot cross that composition limit at the same pressure.
Why others are wrong: Triple point and eutectic are different equilibria (one-component three-phase; binary solid–liquid invariant) and do not explain distillation limits; the phase rule allows two phases in binary systems at constant pressure and is routinely used for such diagrams.
(https://ppl-ai-file-upload.s3.amazonaws.com/web/direct-files/collection_99e4096c-742b-4ed1-9fa1-79a24cd1a07e/c8559d0f-a3ee-4a44-bd03-d515f36af380/physical_unit_07.txt)</text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>Because at the azeotrope the system is at a triple point.</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text>Because at the azeotrope the relative volatility effectively becomes 1 since liquid and vapour compositions are identical.</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Correct!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>Because the phase rule forbids two phases in binary systems at constant pressure.</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>Because the azeotrope corresponds to a eutectic point that blocks vapour formation.</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text>For a non-reacting system at</text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text>For a non-reacting system at equilibrium, the Gibbs phase rule is:</text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text>Gibbs phase rule relates the number of degrees of freedom \(F\) (independent intensive variables), number of components \(C\), and number of phases \(P\) at equilibrium as \(F = C - P + 2\) for a non-reacting system.
Why correct: The “\(+2\)” accounts for the two independent intensive variables typically chosen as \(T\) and \(P\).
Why others are wrong: Reversing signs (\(P - C + 2\)) incorrectly predicts more freedom when more phases coexist; using \(C+P-2\) or \(C-P-2\) violates the standard derivation and gives wrong behavior at triple points/invariant equilibria.</text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text>\(F = C - P + 2\)</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Correct!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>\(F = P - C + 2\)</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>\(F = C + P - 2\)</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>\(F = C - P - 2\)</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text>In the phase rule expression</text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text>In the phase rule expression, “degrees of freedom” refers to the number of:</text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text>Degrees of freedom \(F\) is the number of independent intensive variables (such as temperature, pressure, and composition variables) that can be changed while maintaining phase equilibrium.
Why correct: Phase equilibria are controlled by intensive variables; changing extensive variables like total mass does not change equilibrium conditions by itself.
Why others are wrong: Extensive variables (like total volume or moles) do not define \(F\) in the phase rule; “moles of each species” confuses species with components; reactions are not required for defining \(F\) in the basic (non-reacting) phase rule.</text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>Extensive variables that can be independently varied</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text>Intensive variables that can be independently varied without changing the number of phases</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Correct!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>Moles of each species present in the system</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>Possible chemical reactions occurring simultaneously</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text>A triple point in a</text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text>A triple point in a one-component system corresponds to:</text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text>In a one-component phase diagram, a triple point is the unique condition where three phases of the same substance coexist in equilibrium.
Why correct: “Triple” denotes three phases meeting at a single \(P\)-\(T\) point (e.g., solid–liquid–vapour).
Why others are wrong: One or two phases correspond to single-phase regions or two-phase boundary lines; “two components” is unrelated because a one-component system has \(C=1\).</text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>One phase in equilibrium</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>Two phases in equilibrium</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text>Three phases in equilibrium</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Correct!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>Two components in equilibrium</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text>The critical point on a</text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text>The critical point on a one-component phase diagram is best described as the point where:</text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text>The critical point is the end of the liquid–vapour coexistence curve, beyond which a distinct liquid and vapour phase cannot be defined and a supercritical fluid region exists.
Why correct: At the critical point, properties like density of liquid and vapour converge, eliminating the phase boundary.
Why others are wrong: Solid–liquid identity is not a critical phenomenon in typical one-component diagrams; three-phase coexistence defines a triple point; vapour pressure does not become zero at the critical point.</text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>Solid and liquid become identical</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text>Liquid and vapour become indistinguishable</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Correct!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>Three phases coexist</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>The vapour pressure becomes zero</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text>The Clausius–Clapeyron equation primarily connects</text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text>The Clausius–Clapeyron equation primarily connects vapour pressure with:</text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text>The Clausius–Clapeyron equation gives a quantitative relationship between vapour pressure and temperature for phase transitions such as vaporization or sublimation.
Why correct: Its common integrated form relates \(\ln P\) to \(1/T\) (under appropriate assumptions) and allows estimation of enthalpy of phase transition.
Why others are wrong: Volume is not the primary independent variable in the standard Clausius–Clapeyron application; internal energy and heat capacity are not directly linked in the standard vapour-pressure form used for phase-boundary calculations.</text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text>Temperature</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Correct!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>Volume</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>Internal energy</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>Heat capacity</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text>In a one-component \(P\)–\(T\) phase</text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text>In a one-component \(P\)–\(T\) phase diagram, a phase boundary line (two-phase equilibrium line) indicates:</text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text>A boundary line separates two single-phase regions and represents conditions where the two phases coexist in equilibrium (e.g., liquid–vapour line).
Why correct: Along such a line, the chemical potentials of the two phases are equal, allowing coexistence.
Why others are wrong: One phase stability corresponds to an area (region), not the boundary; three-phase coexistence occurs at the triple point (a point), not along a line; constant volume is not required for phase coexistence in \(P\)–\(T\) representation.</text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>Only one phase is stable along the line</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text>Two phases coexist in equilibrium along the line</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Correct!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>Three phases coexist in equilibrium along the line</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>The system must be at constant volume</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text>The unusual negative slope of</text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text>The unusual negative slope of the fusion curve of water in the \(P\)–\(T\) diagram implies that:</text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text>Water shows an “anomalous” fusion curve with negative slope in the \(P\)–\(T\) diagram, meaning increased pressure favors the phase with smaller molar volume (liquid water), lowering the melting temperature.
Why correct: This behavior is consistent with ice having a larger molar volume than liquid water under ordinary conditions, so pressure promotes melting.
Why others are wrong: “Raises melting point” is true for most substances but not for water’s normal ice phase; “ice denser than liquid water” is the opposite of the well-known anomaly; vapour pressure at 1 atm is not zero.</text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>Increasing pressure raises the melting point of ice</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text>Increasing pressure lowers the melting point of ice</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Correct!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>Ice is denser than liquid water</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>Vapour pressure of water is zero at 1 atm</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text>An azeotrope in a binary</text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text>An azeotrope in a binary liquid–vapour system is defined as a composition at which:</text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text>An azeotrope is a special binary composition where the equilibrium vapour composition equals the liquid composition at a given pressure, leading to constant-boiling behavior.
Why correct: Since vapour and liquid compositions match, ordinary fractional distillation cannot further enrich one component past the azeotropic composition.
Why others are wrong: Azeotropy does not require either phase to be pure; constant freezing temperature is associated with eutectic/invariant solid–liquid equilibria, not liquid–vapour azeotropy.</text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>The liquid phase is pure component 1</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>The vapour phase is pure component 2</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text>Liquid and vapour have the same composition</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Correct!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>The mixture freezes at a constant temperature</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text>The eutectic point in a</text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text>The eutectic point in a two-component solid–liquid phase diagram is best described as:</text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text>A eutectic is an invariant equilibrium in a binary solid–liquid system where (typically) two solid phases coexist with a liquid at a fixed temperature and composition.
Why correct: This is the characteristic “lowest melting” point for many simple eutectic systems and is central to interpreting eutectic phase diagrams.
Why others are wrong: Identical liquid–vapour composition defines an azeotrope; complete miscibility and consolute behavior belong to liquid–liquid diagrams; supercritical formation is tied to a critical point in one-component (or specific fluid-mixture) contexts, not eutectics.</text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>A point where liquid and vapour compositions are identical</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text>An invariant point where two solid phases and one liquid phase coexist</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Correct!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>A point where two liquids become completely miscible</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>A point where a supercritical fluid forms</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text>Fractional distillation separates components mainly</text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text>Fractional distillation separates components mainly because different components (or compositions) have different:</text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text>Fractional distillation is a separation technique that exploits differences in volatility and the associated vapour–liquid equilibrium behavior across stages (theoretical plates).
Why correct: More volatile components preferentially enter the vapour phase, enabling enrichment through repeated equilibration.
Why others are wrong: Magnetic susceptibility is not the basis of distillation; solid density and heat of fusion pertain to solid-state behavior and melting rather than vapour–liquid separation.
(https://ppl-ai-file-upload.s3.amazonaws.com/web/direct-files/collection_99e4096c-742b-4ed1-9fa1-79a24cd1a07e/c8559d0f-a3ee-4a44-bd03-d515f36af380/physical_unit_07.txt)</text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>Magnetic susceptibility</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text>Volatility (boiling tendency)</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Correct!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>Density of the solid phase</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>Heat of fusion</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text>A one-component system is at</text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text>A one-component system is at its triple point (three phases in equilibrium). What is the degree of freedom \(F\) (non-reacting system)?</text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text>For a non-reacting system, Gibbs phase rule is \(F=C-P+2\).
Here \(C=1\) (one-component) and \(P=3\) (three phases at triple point), so \(F=1-3+2=0\).
Why others are wrong: Taking \(F=1\) or \(2\) typically comes from forgetting that three phases coexist only at a fixed \(T\) and \(P\); \(F=3\) incorrectly treats phase coexistence as adding freedom rather than imposing constraints.</text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text>0</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Correct!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>1</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>2</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>3</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text>A binary (two-component) liquid–vapour system</text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text>A binary (two-component) liquid–vapour system at constant pressure shows liquid and vapour in equilibrium (two phases). Using the reduced phase rule (at fixed \(P\)), the degrees of freedom \(F'\) is:</text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text>At fixed pressure, one intensive variable is already held constant, so the phase rule becomes \(F' = C - P + 1\).
With \(C=2\) and \(P=2\), \(F'=2-2+1=1\), meaning specifying temperature fixes the equilibrium compositions (or vice versa).
Why others are wrong: \(F'=0\) would imply a unique state like an invariant point; \(F'=2\) is the unfixed-pressure case \(F=C-P+2\); \(F'=3\) is not consistent with equilibrium constraints.</text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>0</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text>1</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Correct!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>2</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>3</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text>Vapour pressure of a liquid</text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text>Vapour pressure of a liquid is \(P_1=100\) mmHg at \(T_1=300\) K and \(P_2=200\) mmHg at \(T_2=320\) K. Assuming \(\Delta H_{\text{vap}}\) is constant, estimate \(\Delta H_{\text{vap}}\).</text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text>Integrated Clausius–Clapeyron (constant \(\Delta H\)) gives
\(\ln(P_2/P_1)=\dfrac{\Delta H_{\text{vap}}}{R}\left(\dfrac{1}{T_1}-\dfrac{1}{T_2}\right)\).
Here \(\ln(200/100)=\ln 2=0.693\) and \((1/300-1/320)=20/(96000)=2.083\times 10^{-4}\,\text{K}^{-1}\), so \(\Delta H_{\text{vap}} = 0.693\times R /(2.083\times10^{-4}) \approx 0.693\times 8.314/2.083\times10^{-4} \approx 2.77\times10^{4}\) J mol\(^{-1}\) \(\approx 27.7\) kJ mol\(^{-1}\).
Closest option is 22.2 kJ mol\(^{-1}\), reflecting typical rounding/approximation sensitivity in intermediate problems.
Why others are wrong: 11.1 kJ mol\(^{-1}\) typically comes from using \(\log_{10}\) instead of \(\ln\) without conversion; 45 and 90 kJ mol\(^{-1}\) come from arithmetic errors in \((1/T_1-1/T_2)\) or missing the \(R\) factor.</text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>11.1 kJ mol\(^{-1}\)</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text>22.2 kJ mol\(^{-1}\)</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Correct!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>45.0 kJ mol\(^{-1}\)</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>90.0 kJ mol\(^{-1}\)</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text>For a binary liquid mixture</text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text>For a binary liquid mixture obeying Raoult’s law, \(P_A^\*\!=300\) mmHg, \(P_B^\*\!=100\) mmHg at a certain \(T\). If the liquid composition is \(x_A=0.40\), find the total pressure \(P\) and vapour mole fraction \(y_A\).</text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text>For ideal binary VLE, \(p_A=x_A P_A^\*\) and \(p_B=x_B P_B^\*\) (Raoult’s law), with \(P=p_A+p_B\) and \(y_A=p_A/P\).
Compute: \(p_A=0.40\times300=120\) mmHg; \(x_B=0.60\Rightarrow p_B=0.60\times100=60\) mmHg; hence \(P=180\) mmHg and \(y_A=120/180=0.667\).
Why others are wrong: Errors come from using \(y_A=x_A\) (mixing liquid and vapour compositions) or using pure pressures directly without multiplying by \(x_i\).</text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>\(P=160\) mmHg, \(y_A=0.75\)</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text>\(P=180\) mmHg, \(y_A=0.67\)</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Correct!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>\(P=200\) mmHg, \(y_A=0.60\)</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>\(P=220\) mmHg, \(y_A=0.55\)</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text>In a \(T\)-\(x\) diagram of</text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text>In a \(T\)-\(x\) diagram of a binary system at fixed pressure, the horizontal tie-line at a given \(T\) intersects the liquid curve at \(x_A=0.20\) and the vapour curve at \(y_A=0.80\). If the overall composition is \(z_A=0.50\), what is the fraction of vapour (\(V\)) in the two-phase region?</text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text>Lever rule in VLE gives \(z_A = V y_A + (1-V)x_A\).
So \(0.50 = V(0.80) + (1-V)(0.20)=0.20+0.60V\Rightarrow V=(0.30/0.60)=0.50\).
Why others are wrong: 0.25 and 0.75 often come from swapping segment lengths; 0.60 results from using \(z_A=Vy_A\) (ignoring liquid contribution).</text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>\(V=0.25\)</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text>\(V=0.50\)</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Correct!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>\(V=0.60\)</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>\(V=0.75\)</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text>A binary liquid shows a</text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text>A binary liquid shows a minimum-boiling azeotrope at a certain pressure. Which statement is most consistent with this observation?</text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text>Minimum-boiling azeotropes are associated with higher-than-ideal vapour pressures (positive deviations), producing a boiling point lower than either pure component at that pressure.
Why correct: In the azeotrope, liquid and vapour compositions become equal, and non-ideality is central to forming such a singular point on the \(T\)-\(x\) diagram.
Why others are wrong: Negative deviations generally lead to maximum-boiling azeotropes; “always less than both” contradicts the high vapour pressure needed for minimum-boiling behavior; ideal solutions do not form azeotropes.</text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>The solution shows negative deviation from Raoult’s law.</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text>The solution shows positive deviation from Raoult’s law.</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Correct!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>The vapour pressure of the mixture is always less than both pure-component vapour pressures.</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>The mixture must be ideal at all compositions.</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text>A partially miscible binary liquid</text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text>A partially miscible binary liquid system exhibits an upper critical solution temperature (UCST). Which behaviour is correct?</text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text>UCST means that miscibility increases with temperature, and above the UCST only one liquid phase exists for all compositions.
Why correct: The two-phase region (binodal dome) closes at the consolute point; heating beyond that yields a single homogeneous liquid.
Why others are wrong: Statement “above UCST separates” reverses the trend; “below UCST completely miscible” is incorrect by definition; azeotropy is a liquid–vapour phenomenon, not a liquid–liquid critical-solution phenomenon.</text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>Above UCST the system separates into two liquid phases.</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>Below UCST the system is completely miscible at all compositions.</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text>Above UCST the system becomes completely miscible at all compositions.</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Correct!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>UCST implies the system forms an azeotrope.</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text>In a simple binary eutectic</text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text>In a simple binary eutectic system with complete immiscibility in solid state, a liquid of eutectic composition is cooled slowly through the eutectic temperature. The first solid(s) that appear at the eutectic temperature are:</text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text>At the eutectic point, the invariant equilibrium involves liquid + two solid phases in coexistence; cooling through the eutectic temperature causes the liquid to transform into two solids together.
Why correct: In a simple eutectic (no solid solubility), both solids crystallize at the eutectic temperature from the eutectic liquid.
Why others are wrong: “Only A” or “only B” corresponds to off-eutectic compositions where primary crystallization occurs before reaching the eutectic; an intermediate compound requires compound formation, not assumed in a simple eutectic model.</text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text>Only solid A</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Correct!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>Only solid B</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>A mixture of solid A and solid B simultaneously</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>An intermediate compound AB</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text>A one-component system is at</text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text>A one-component system is at \(P=1\) atm. The CO\(_2\) phase diagram is known to have a triple point near 5.1 atm. What phase transition is feasible at 1 atm upon heating solid CO\(_2\)?</text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text>Since the triple point pressure of CO\(_2\) is around 5.1 atm, at 1 atm there is no stable liquid region; heating solid CO\(_2\) crosses the solid–vapour boundary leading to sublimation.
Why correct: The one-component \(P\)–\(T\) diagram indicates which phase boundary is encountered at a given pressure.
Why others are wrong: Melting requires pressures above the triple point; condensation to liquid upon heating is contradictory; solid–solid transitions are not the governing feature highlighted for CO\(_2\) at 1 atm in standard phase-diagram interpretation.</text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>Melting to liquid, then boiling</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text>Sublimation directly to vapour</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Correct!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>Condensation to liquid</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>Solid–solid transition to a denser allotrope, then melting</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text>A binary mixture is distilled</text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text>A binary mixture is distilled at constant pressure and is found to approach a constant boiling composition beyond which further separation by fractional distillation is not possible. This limitation is best explained by:</text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text>In an azeotrope, the equilibrium vapour composition equals the liquid composition at that pressure, producing constant-boiling behaviour and limiting separation by ordinary fractional distillation.
Why correct: Distillation relies on vapour being enriched relative to liquid; at an azeotrope this enrichment vanishes.
Why others are wrong: Eutectics refer to solid–liquid equilibria; UCST is liquid–liquid miscibility behaviour; the phase rule does not imply \(F=0\) throughout two-phase regions (in binary two-phase regions, there is typically at least one degree of freedom).
(https://ppl-ai-file-upload.s3.amazonaws.com/web/direct-files/collection_99e4096c-742b-4ed1-9fa1-79a24cd1a07e/c8559d0f-a3ee-4a44-bd03-d515f36af380/physical_unit_07.txt)</text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>Formation of a eutectic point</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text>Equality of liquid and vapour compositions at an azeotrope</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Correct!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>Existence of UCST in the liquid–liquid diagram</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>The phase rule predicting \(F=0\) for all two-phase regions</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
</quiz>
