<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<quiz>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text><![CDATA[In hemoglobin, cooperative O\(_2\) binding]]></text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[In hemoglobin, cooperative O\(_2\) binding is coupled to a structural transition. Which mechanism best links ligand field effects at the heme iron to cooperativity and allosteric regulation?]]></text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Cooperative binding in hemoglobin is explicitly tied to allosteric regulation, and the heme site is where O\(_2\) binding perturbs iron coordination/electronic structure (a ligand-field/coordination-chemistry issue) that can be communicated to the protein scaffold.  A coordination-driven structural perturbation provides a chemically grounded route for a local binding event to influence quaternary structure and hence other binding sites, matching the idea of cooperativity emphasized for hemoglobin.  Oxidation of Fe(II) to Fe(III) would undermine reversible oxygen binding rather than enable it, so a redox-change requirement is inconsistent with reversible transport.  Membrane electrochemical gradients (Nernst potential) are relevant to ion transport, not to the intraprotein allostery of a soluble oxygen carrier.]]></text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[O\(_2\) binding increases electron density on porphyrin, forcing Fe to move further out of the porphyrin plane and stabilizing the low-affinity state]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[O\(_2\) binding changes the heme Fe(II) electronic structure in a way that alters Fe position relative to the porphyrin plane, transmitting a conformational change to the protein and shifting affinity at other subunits]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Correct!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[O\(_2\) binding requires oxidation of Fe(II) to Fe(III), and the resulting charge change drives subunit rearrangement responsible for cooperativity]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[O\(_2\) binding is independent of heme coordination chemistry; cooperativity arises only from changes in membrane potential (Nernst-type control)]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text><![CDATA[Consider biological electron transfer in]]></text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Consider biological electron transfer in proteins where both redox potentials (thermodynamics) and electron tunneling (kinetics) matter. Which statement is most consistent with how an electron transfer step can be thermodynamically allowed but kinetically slow?]]></text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[The unit separates electron-transfer thermodynamics (redox potentials) from mechanisms and rate constants (electron tunneling/transfer kinetics), so it is valid for a reaction to have favorable driving force yet exhibit a small rate constant due to poor electronic coupling through the protein matrix.  Electron tunneling is a distance- and pathway-sensitive kinetic phenomenon, so increasing separation can slow transfer without reversing thermodynamic direction.  A favorable potential difference does not automatically imply ATP synthesis at that exact step because coupling to ATP production involves the broader chain architecture (including proton pumping/chemiosmosis).  Slow kinetics do not require equal redox potentials; they can arise from kinetic barriers and weak coupling even with substantial driving force.]]></text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[If the donor has a lower redox potential than the acceptor, electron transfer is spontaneous and always fast regardless of distance]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Electron tunneling rate can decrease strongly with increasing donor–acceptor separation even when the redox potential difference favors transfer]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Correct!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[A favorable redox potential difference guarantees that ATP synthesis must occur in the same step]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[If electron tunneling is slow, the redox potentials must be equal]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text><![CDATA[Nitrogenase must deliver multiple electrons]]></text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Nitrogenase must deliver multiple electrons and protons to reduce N\(_2\) to NH\(_3\) and is regulated by strong biological constraints. Which explanation best integrates the need for ATP consumption with electron/proton flow and oxygen sensitivity?]]></text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[The unit highlights nitrogenase complex structure (Fe protein + MoFe protein), the FeMo-co active site, and the electron/proton flow needed for N\(_2\) to NH\(_3\), along with oxygen sensitivity as a biological constraint.  A key integrated idea is that ATP usage supports the demanding catalytic cycle by gating/energizing electron delivery steps to the active site where multi-electron chemistry occurs.  Oxygen is described as problematic (sensitivity/regulation), not as an activator, so making O\(_2\) a required trigger conflicts with the stated constraint.  Protonation and reduction of N\(_2\) are not simple bulk-solution processes; they depend on the metal cofactor environment and controlled delivery of reducing equivalents.]]></text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[ATP hydrolysis is required because FeMo-co cannot accept electrons unless oxygen is present as a mandatory activator]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[ATP hydrolysis in the Fe protein is coupled to controlled electron transfer into the MoFe protein/FeMo-co, enabling stepwise multi-electron/proton chemistry for N\(_2\) reduction while the enzyme remains vulnerable to O\(_2\) damage]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Correct!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[ATP hydrolysis directly protonates N\(_2\) in solution, while the metal cluster only serves as a spectator binding site]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[ATP hydrolysis is only needed to regenerate NAD\(^+\) for zinc enzymes and is unrelated to N\(_2\) reduction]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text><![CDATA[A researcher must choose a]]></text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[A researcher must choose a biological redox cofactor for fast, long-range electron transfer between proteins with minimal chemical reactivity toward substrates (pure electron transfer role). Which choice and rationale best fit the classification of metal centers emphasized in the unit?]]></text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[The copper section explicitly distinguishes Type 1 copper centers (blue copper proteins) and connects them to electron transfer, making them the best match for a dedicated electron-transfer module.  Zinc enzymes in the unit are framed around structural/catalytic roles (often Lewis-acid chemistry) rather than redox cycling, so assigning Zn as a redox shuttle is inconsistent with typical bioinorganic roles discussed.  Mg(II) is highlighted for ATP-related catalysis and structural roles, not for redox chemistry or direct O\(_2\) activation in electron-transfer chains.  Vitamin B\(_{12}\) chemistry is emphasized for methyl transfer and radical/rearrangement mechanisms, not as a universal long-range one-electron transfer cofactor.]]></text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Zn(II) center, because Zn readily cycles oxidation states and enables rapid electron transport]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Type 1 copper center (blue copper protein), because it is specialized for electron transfer and is classified accordingly in copper metalloenzymes]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Correct!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Mg(II) center, because Mg activates O\(_2\) and therefore accelerates electron flow]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Vitamin B\(_{12}\) cobalt center, because all cobalt enzymes are dedicated solely to one-electron transfer chains]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text><![CDATA[Metal homeostasis and correct metal]]></text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Metal homeostasis and correct metal insertion are crucial for enzyme function. Which scenario best illustrates how metal homeostasis links to both catalysis and prevention of incorrect chemistry in cells?]]></text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[The unit includes metal homeostasis (storage, sequestration, detoxification) and separately emphasizes iron–sulfur clusters as electron mediators, so correct handling of iron connects directly to both preventing harmful chemistry and enabling essential electron transfer.  Zinc is typically redox-inert under physiological conditions and is not the classic driver of Fenton-type radical formation, so portraying Zn as the main Fenton hazard reflects a mechanistic misconception.  Ferritin is associated with iron storage rather than magnesium, and Mg does not normally undergo biologically relevant redox cycling in enzymes as framed by the Mg-metalloenzyme section.  Copper homeostasis is emphasized because excess copper can be toxic; simply increasing free copper would not guarantee improved enzyme performance and can disrupt metal balance and protein integrity.]]></text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Sequestering redox-active iron limits uncontrolled side reactions, while ensuring proper delivery allows iron–sulfur clusters to function as electron mediators in electron transfer chains]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Correct!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Sequestering zinc is necessary mainly to prevent Zn(II) from generating reactive oxygen species via Fenton-type chemistry]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Storing magnesium in ferritin is essential because Mg(II) must be protected from oxidation to Mg(III)]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Increasing free copper concentration always improves cytochrome oxidase efficiency because more metal guarantees faster catalysis without toxicity]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
</quiz>
