<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<quiz>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text><![CDATA[Both XeF₂ and ICl₃ are]]></text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Both XeF₂ and ICl₃ are commonly explained using multi-center bonding ideas in addition to VSEPR; which statement best captures the shared bonding logic that helps rationalize their hypervalent electron counts?]]></text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[The unit explicitly frames xenon fluorides and several interhalogens in terms of hypervalency and multi-center bonding, including the three-center four-electron model.  This delocalized-bond picture allows electron-rich descriptions without forcing all bonding into localized two-center bonds while still connecting to VSEPR-based shapes.  Treating d-orbital participation as the only explanation conflicts with the unit’s emphasis that bonding models exist alongside an explicit “d-orbital participation debate/current understanding.”  A purely ionic picture does not align with the unit’s focus on structural determination, bonding models, and spectroscopic characterization for these species.  A strict octet-only localized bonding view is inconsistent with the unit’s repeated treatment of “expanded octets/hypervalency” for noble-gas fluorides and interhalogens.]]></text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Both can be rationalized using three-center four-electron bonding involving a delocalized set of electrons over three atoms, consistent with “expanded octet” behavior.]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Correct!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Both require true d-orbital covalent bonding as the only valid explanation for bonds beyond an octet.]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Both must be purely ionic in the solid state, so any covalent bonding model is unnecessary.]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Both strictly follow the octet rule with only localized two-center two-electron bonds on the central atom.]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text><![CDATA[A sample shows a single]]></text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[A sample shows a single ¹⁹F NMR resonance for an interhalogen that is VSEPR-predicted to contain more than one distinct fluorine environment at a static structure; which inference is most defensible using the unit’s emphasis on variable-temperature NMR and structure determination?]]></text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[The unit explicitly connects ¹⁹F NMR to xenon and interhalogen compounds and also highlights variable-temperature NMR studies as a way to interpret spectra when structures are not rigid.  If a static VSEPR picture predicts inequivalent fluorines, a single observed resonance can be rationalized by rapid interchange that makes fluorines equivalent on the measurement timescale.  Declaring VSEPR “invalid” overreaches, since the unit repeatedly uses extended VSEPR as a primary structure-prediction tool for these exact systems.  The inference about “must be a noble-gas oxide” is unrelated to the spectroscopy framing in the unit and incorrectly restricts NMR behavior to a compound class.  A single resonance does not uniquely imply linearity; it can also arise from symmetry or dynamic averaging in non-linear hypervalent systems discussed here.]]></text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[The molecule is undergoing dynamic exchange that averages fluorine environments on the NMR timescale, and variable-temperature ¹⁹F NMR can test this by changing the exchange rate.]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Correct!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[VSEPR theory is invalid for interhalogens, so geometry cannot be inferred at all from electron counting.]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[The compound must be a noble-gas oxide, because only oxides give one NMR signal.]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[The single resonance proves the molecule is linear, because linear molecules always have one fluorine environment.]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text><![CDATA[CN⁻ is treated as a]]></text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[CN⁻ is treated as a pseudohalide and also as a ligand with specific bonding character; which statement best links these ideas to explain why CN⁻ forms strong coordination complexes compared with many simple anions?]]></text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[The unit explicitly lists CN⁻ under pseudohalogens and separately emphasizes its linear bonding description plus “π-donor and σ-acceptor character” and “coordination chemistry and complex formation.”  Connecting these points supports the idea that CN⁻ can participate in strong, structured bonding to metal centers rather than behaving as a purely ionic spectator.  Treating CN⁻ as noble-gas-like contradicts the unit’s placement of CN⁻ in a section focused on reactivity and coordination behavior.  The claim that pseudohalogens “never coordinate” conflicts with the unit’s explicit learning objective to analyze complex formation and coordination behavior of pseudohalides.  Hydrogen bonding is not the central explanation for CN⁻ complex formation in the unit’s framing, which focuses on electronic structure and coordination chemistry instead.]]></text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[CN⁻ is linear with multiple bonding and is described here as having π-donor and σ-acceptor character, supporting strong, directional metal–ligand interactions and extensive complex formation.]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Correct!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[CN⁻ behaves like a noble gas atom because it has a filled valence shell, so it rarely binds to metals.]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[CN⁻ cannot act as a ligand because pseudohalogens only undergo displacement reactions and never coordinate.]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[CN⁻ forms strong complexes only due to hydrogen bonding, which dominates its chemistry in solution.]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text><![CDATA[Square-planar geometries are highlighted for]]></text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Square-planar geometries are highlighted for certain polyinterhalogen ions; which electron-counting/VSEPR-consistent statement best explains why ICl₄⁻ is square planar rather than tetrahedral?]]></text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[The unit explicitly treats polyinterhalogen ions using “charge and electron counting methods” and emphasizes “square planar geometry and lone pairs” along with “VSEPR application with negative charge.”  Including the −1 charge in electron counting increases the central-atom electron pair count, making lone-pair effects sufficient to drive square-planar shapes for ions like ICl₄⁻.  Assuming all four-coordinate species are tetrahedral ignores the unit’s direct inclusion of square-planar polyinterhalogen ions and square-planar hypervalent systems.  The claim about iodine being unable to expand coordination number conflicts with the unit’s broader discussion of high coordination numbers in interhalogens and polyinterhalogen chemistry.  Assigning fixed 90° angles to chlorine is not a valid structural principle in this context; the unit’s structure determination relies on VSEPR, electron counting, and spectroscopy rather than “element-forced” angles.]]></text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Counting the negative charge in the VSEPR electron inventory yields an AX₄E₂ situation on iodine, giving an octahedral electron-pair arrangement with a square-planar molecular shape.]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Correct!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[ICl₄⁻ must be tetrahedral because all four-coordinate species are tetrahedral by default.]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[ICl₄⁻ is square planar only because iodine cannot expand its coordination number beyond 4.]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[ICl₄⁻ is square planar because chlorine always forces 90° bond angles in any compound.]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text><![CDATA[Xenon oxides (XeO₃, XeO₄) are]]></text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Xenon oxides (XeO₃, XeO₄) are presented as strong oxidizers with notable instability; which integrated explanation best matches the unit’s structure–property emphasis?]]></text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[The unit explicitly links xenon oxides/oxyfluorides to oxidizing ability and also emphasizes instability and explosive decomposition patterns for XeO₃ and XeO₄.  Combining “high oxidation state” reasoning with structure–property relationships aligns with the unit’s focus on predicting reactivity from structure and comparing oxidizing/redox properties across classes.  Invoking xenon’s inertness as the reason for stability contradicts the unit’s central milestone that noble gases can form reactive compounds and the explicit oxidizing behavior assigned to xenon oxides.  The geometry assignments in the incorrect statement are reversed relative to the unit’s presentation (XeO₃ pyramidal; XeO₄ tetrahedral), and geometry alone is not sufficient to explain oxidizing power without oxidation-state/redox context.  Hydrogen bonding is not the driver emphasized for these inorganic oxidizers in the unit, which instead stresses bonding, oxidation states, and decomposition/reactivity patterns.
(https://ppl-ai-file-upload.s3.amazonaws.com/web/direct-files/collection_99e4096c-742b-4ed1-9fa1-79a24cd1a07e/26588078-225d-4384-895e-f69546b64bf1/inorganic_unit_03.txt)]]></text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[High xenon oxidation states combined with structural/bonding features in oxygen-containing xenon compounds make them powerful oxidants, and their decomposition can be energetically favorable, contributing to instability and explosive tendencies.]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Correct!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[XeO₃ and XeO₄ are stable mainly because xenon is inert, so they cannot act as oxidizing agents.]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[XeO₃ is tetrahedral while XeO₄ is pyramidal, and this shape reversal explains all reactivity trends.]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Their oxidizing behavior is unrelated to oxidation state and instead arises only from hydrogen bonding networks.]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
</quiz>
