<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<quiz>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text><![CDATA[An octahedral complex shows one]]></text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[An octahedral complex shows one or more weak d–d absorption bands even though it is centrosymmetric. The most appropriate explanation is:]]></text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[In centrosymmetric complexes, d–d transitions are Laporte-forbidden, so their intensities are intrinsically weak.  The relaxation of selection rules can occur via vibronic coupling (and also via spin–orbit coupling), which allows weak intensity borrowing.  Charge-transfer transitions are a different class of transitions and are not required to explain every weak band observed in a centrosymmetric complex.  The spin selection rule can make transitions spin-forbidden (weaker), not automatically intense.  Racah parameters describe electron–electron repulsion and covalency trends (nephelauxetic effect), not a “switch” that becomes zero due to centrosymmetry.]]></text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Laporte rule is strictly obeyed in all complexes, so any observed band must be charge-transfer]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Vibronic coupling can relax the Laporte-forbidden nature of d–d transitions]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Correct!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Spin selection rule forces all d–d bands to be intense]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Racah parameter \(B\) becomes zero in centrosymmetric complexes, enabling transitions]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text><![CDATA[A \(d^9\) octahedral complex commonly]]></text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[A \(d^9\) octahedral complex commonly shows strong tetragonal distortion. Which statement best captures the underlying cause-and-effect chain?]]></text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Jahn–Teller distortion is expected when the electronic ground state is orbitally degenerate, and octahedral \(d^9\) is a classic strong case.  For \(d^9\), uneven occupancy of the \(e_g\) set creates an energetic incentive to distort (often axial elongation or compression) to remove degeneracy and lower total energy.  The effect is not restricted to fully filled shells; it is associated with degeneracy and partial occupancy.  The relative ordering \(t_{2g}\) vs \(e_g\) in octahedral fields is fixed by geometry, but the distortion is specifically tied to degeneracy removal, not a reversal of ordering.  Counterions can influence lattice strain in solids, but the primary driver described here is electronic structure.]]></text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Jahn–Teller effect removes degeneracy in a partially occupied \(e_g\) level, stabilizing a distorted geometry]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Correct!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Jahn–Teller effect occurs only when all orbitals are fully filled, forcing symmetry breaking]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Distortion happens because \(t_{2g}\) orbitals are always higher in energy than \(e_g\) orbitals in octahedral fields]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Distortion is driven primarily by counterion size, not by electronic structure]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text><![CDATA[Two cobalt(III) octahedral complexes have]]></text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Two cobalt(III) octahedral complexes have similar thermodynamic stability constants, but one is substitution-inert while the other is substitution-labile. Which interpretation best matches coordination chemistry principles?]]></text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Thermodynamic stability refers to equilibrium preference, while kinetic stability refers to reaction rate (lability/inertness), so they are not equivalent properties.  Ligand field effects and CFSE are part of the framework used to rationalize stability and reactivity trends in coordination complexes.  Similar equilibrium constants do not force the same activation barriers, so substitution rates can differ substantially even if thermodynamic stabilities are comparable.  Inertness is not determined only by charge; electronic structure and ligand field effects are central to mechanistic trends.  Inert complexes can still be thermodynamically stable, so inertness does not imply thermodynamic instability.]]></text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Kinetic stability (inert/labile) can differ from thermodynamic stability because they describe rate vs equilibrium, and ligand field/CFSE can influence lability]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Correct!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Similar thermodynamic stability constants guarantee identical substitution rates]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Inertness depends only on charge of the complex ion and never on electronic configuration]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[If a complex is substitution-inert, it must be thermodynamically unstable]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text><![CDATA[A redox reaction between two]]></text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[A redox reaction between two coordination complexes proceeds only when a ligand capable of bridging is present, and products show ligand transfer consistent with a transient bridged intermediate. The electron-transfer pathway is best classified as:]]></text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Inner-sphere electron transfer involves a bridging ligand that links the two metal centers during the electron-transfer event.  The requirement of a bridge and evidence consistent with a bridged intermediate align with the inner-sphere description.  Outer-sphere electron transfer typically occurs without forming a bridging ligand connection between the coordination spheres.  Dissociative substitution is a ligand exchange classification and does not describe the hallmark bridging-ligand requirement of inner-sphere redox.  Bailar twist is a stereochemical isomerisation pathway in octahedral complexes, not an electron-transfer mechanism classification.]]></text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Outer-sphere electron transfer]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Inner-sphere electron transfer]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Correct!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Purely dissociative substitution (D) with no redox involvement]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Bailar twist-driven electron transfer]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text><![CDATA[A complex containing an M–M]]></text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[A complex containing an M–M quadruple bond is discussed using an MO picture with σ, π, and δ components. Which qualitative statement is most consistent with this description?]]></text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[The metal–metal multiple bond topic explicitly includes σ, π, and δ components, and quadruple bonds are rationalized by including a δ component in addition to σ and π bonding.  Treating δ as “σ counted twice” is not a valid symmetry-based MO description of bonding components.  Quadruple bonding is not restricted to \(d^{10}\) metals; it is treated using electron counting and MO descriptions of M–M bonding.  The stated learning objective links M–M bonding to magnetic and spectroscopic signatures, so claiming no effect contradicts the expected property correlations.
(https://ppl-ai-file-upload.s3.amazonaws.com/web/direct-files/collection_99e4096c-742b-4ed1-9fa1-79a24cd1a07e/851d31c2-99cf-4f1d-964a-940ec8b03542/inorganic_unit_05.txt)]]></text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[A δ bond arises from side-on overlap of metal d orbitals with appropriate symmetry and contributes to multiple bonding beyond σ and π]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Correct!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[A δ bond is identical to a σ bond but counted twice to increase bond order]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Quadruple bonding is possible only if both metals are \(d^{10}\) so that all bonds are filled]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Metal–metal multiple bonds cannot affect magnetic or spectroscopic properties]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
</quiz>
