<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<quiz>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text><![CDATA[In the context of main-group]]></text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[In the context of main-group chemistry, an “ionic hydride” is best described as:]]></text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Ionic hydrides are typically formed by highly electropositive s-block metals, where hydrogen exists as hydride ion \(\mathrm{H^-}\), giving salt-like solids (high melting points, basic/reactive with water).
The “hydrogen in +1 oxidation state” description matches covalent hydrides like \(\mathrm{HCl}\) or \(\mathrm{H_2O}\), not ionic hydrides.
Hydrogen bonding is an intermolecular interaction and does not define the bonding type in a binary hydride.
Metallic hydrides exist, but they are classified separately from ionic hydrides and involve different bonding models.]]></text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[A salt-like compound containing \(\mathrm{H^-}\) (hydride ion) bonded to an electropositive element]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Correct!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[A compound where hydrogen shows oxidation state \(+1\) bonded to a nonmetal]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[A compound where hydrogen is present only in hydrogen bonds (H-bonding)]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[A compound where hydrogen is bound by metallic bonding in a hydrogen lattice]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text><![CDATA[According to VSEPR theory, a]]></text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[According to VSEPR theory, a species with four bonding pairs and zero lone pairs on the central atom is expected to be:]]></text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[VSEPR predicts tetrahedral geometry for an \(\mathrm{AX_4}\) arrangement (4 electron domains, all bonding, no lone pairs), minimizing electron-pair repulsions in 3D space.
Trigonal planar corresponds to three electron domains (\(\mathrm{AX_3}\)).
Seesaw arises from five electron domains with one lone pair (\(\mathrm{AX_4E}\)).
Square planar is typically associated with \(\mathrm{AX_4E_2}\) electron-domain geometry (octahedral electron arrangement with two lone pairs), not \(\mathrm{AX_4}\).]]></text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Tetrahedral]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Correct!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Trigonal planar]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Seesaw]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Square planar]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text><![CDATA[Which statement best captures the]]></text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Which statement best captures the periodic trend idea most relevant to “reactivity and compound stability” in main-group binary compounds?]]></text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[A key periodic-trends connection used in bonding classification is that larger electronegativity differences generally increase ionic character, affecting structures and reactivity patterns of binary compounds.
Atomic number alone does not dictate covalency; bonding depends strongly on electronegativity, polarizability, oxidation state, and partner element.
Ionization energy influences accessible oxidation states and thus can influence halide stoichiometry and stability trends.
Electron affinity is directly tied to tendencies to accept electrons, so it is relevant to oxidizing behavior in many p-block contexts.]]></text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Higher electronegativity difference generally increases ionic character in bonding]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Correct!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Higher atomic number always implies higher covalency in all compounds]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Ionization energy has no influence on oxidation states in halides]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Electron affinity is unrelated to oxidizing behavior of p-block compounds]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text><![CDATA[A “covalent halide” of a]]></text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[A “covalent halide” of a main-group element is most likely when the central atom is:]]></text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Covalent character in halides increases when the central atom has high polarizing power (small size, higher positive charge), which can distort the electron cloud of the halide and favor covalent bonding character.
Very electropositive and large cations tend to form ionic halides with lattice structures, not primarily covalent molecular halides.
Oxidation state 0 is not a general requirement for forming covalent halides; many covalent halides involve positive oxidation states.
Noble gases can form some compounds under special conditions, but “no bonding” contradicts the idea of a halide compound being formed.]]></text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Small and highly charged (high charge density), strongly polarizing the halide]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Correct!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Very large and very electropositive, forming a lattice with \(\mathrm{X^-}\)]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Always in oxidation state 0]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[A noble gas with filled valence shell and no bonding]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text><![CDATA[Which oxide category is correctly]]></text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Which oxide category is correctly matched with its acid–base behavior description?]]></text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Amphoteric oxides are defined by their ability to react with both acids and bases, reflecting intermediate acid–base character.
Acidic oxides typically react with bases (often forming salts), so “only with acids” is incorrect.
Basic oxides typically react with acids (often forming salts), so “only with bases” is incorrect.
Neutral oxides generally show little acid–base reactivity in water and are not “always strongly basic.”]]></text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Amphoteric oxide: reacts with both acids and bases]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Correct!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Acidic oxide: reacts only with acids, never with bases]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Basic oxide: reacts only with bases, never with acids]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Neutral oxide: always strongly basic in water]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text><![CDATA[For oxoacids of the same]]></text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[For oxoacids of the same central element, acid strength generally increases with:]]></text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[A standard structure–property trend in oxoacids is that adding more oxygen atoms (often raising the central atom oxidation state) increases electron withdrawal and stabilizes the conjugate base, increasing acidity.
The opposite trend (fewer oxygens always stronger) contradicts typical oxoacid series behavior.
Stronger acidity commonly correlates with better stabilization of negative charge through inductive effects and resonance involving oxygen; removing such stabilization does not generally increase acidity.
Within a comparable trend framework, greater electron withdrawal (not lower) promotes acidity; decreasing central electronegativity would not systematically strengthen the acid in the same way.]]></text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Increasing number of oxygen atoms (higher oxidation state / stronger electron withdrawal)]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Correct!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Decreasing number of oxygen atoms, always]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Absence of any \(\mathrm{E=O}\) type bonding contribution (only single bonds)]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Decreasing electronegativity of the central element within the same oxoacid series]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text><![CDATA[An “ionic nitride” is most]]></text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[An “ionic nitride” is most characteristically expected to undergo which reaction with water?]]></text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Ionic nitrides contain \(\mathrm{N^{3-}}\), which is a strong base and readily hydrolyzes in water to give ammonia, a key reactivity pattern for ionic nitrides.
Formation of \(\mathrm{H_2O_2}\) is not the characteristic hydrolysis product expected from \(\mathrm{N^{3-}}\).
Many ionic nitrides are moisture-sensitive; “always inert” is a common misconception.
Oxidation to nitrate may occur under oxidative conditions, but the characteristic first interaction with water is hydrolysis to ammonia.]]></text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Hydrolysis producing ammonia (\(\mathrm{NH_3}\))]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Correct!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Hydrolysis producing hydrogen peroxide (\(\mathrm{H_2O_2}\))]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[No reaction because nitrides are always inert to water]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Only oxidation to nitrate without hydrolysis]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text><![CDATA[Which statement about sulfides is]]></text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Which statement about sulfides is most consistent with main-group sulfide chemistry trends?]]></text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Main-group sulfide chemistry includes diversity in structures and oxidation-state behavior; polysulfides are a known class reflecting sulfur’s ability to form S–S bonds.
Sulfur does not remain fixed at \(-2\) in all sulfur compounds, and sulfides often participate in redox chemistry.
Many sulfides (especially of electropositive elements) are ionic solids, so “always molecular” is incorrect.
Oxidation of sulfides to oxides/oxoacids is a common transformation pathway in sulfur chemistry and related compound classes.]]></text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Sulfides can show varied oxidation states and may form polysulfides under suitable conditions]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Correct!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Sulfides never participate in redox reactions because sulfur is always \(-2\)]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Sulfides are always molecular, never ionic solids]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Sulfides cannot be oxidized to oxides or oxoacids]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text><![CDATA[“Bridge hydrides and multi-center bonding”]]></text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[“Bridge hydrides and multi-center bonding” most directly refers to which bonding description?]]></text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Bridge hydrides are associated with electron-deficient bonding where hydrogen can be shared between two atoms through multi-center bonding descriptions, a key structural concept in some main-group hydride families.
A localized classical double bond to hydrogen is not the typical model used to describe bridge hydrides.
\(\mathrm{H^+}\) in a halide lattice describes an ionic scenario not aligned with bridge-hydride multi-center bonding.
Intermolecular hydrogen bonding is different from the intramolecular multi-center bonding implied by bridge hydrides.]]></text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[A hydrogen atom shared between two main-group atoms in an electron-deficient framework]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Correct!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[A hydrogen atom bonded only by a classical localized double bond to one atom]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[A hydrogen atom present as \(\mathrm{H^+}\) inside an ionic lattice of halides]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[A hydrogen atom participating only in intermolecular hydrogen bonding between molecules]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text><![CDATA[In comparing hydrolysis behavior across]]></text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[In comparing hydrolysis behavior across binary main-group compounds, which statement is most generally reasonable?]]></text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Hydrolysis trends in halides are often rationalized using Lewis acidity of the central atom and bond polarity; many covalent p-block halides hydrolyze readily due to electrophilic central atoms interacting with water.
Not all halides hydrolyze violently; ionic halides like alkali halides are often stable in water (they dissolve but do not hydrolyze appreciably), showing this blanket claim is incorrect.
Halogens do not universally “block” water reactivity; hydrolysis is a standard reaction class for many halides.
Bonding character and Lewis acidity are central determinants of hydrolysis; physical state alone cannot explain observed systematic trends.
(https://ppl-ai-file-upload.s3.amazonaws.com/web/direct-files/collection_99e4096c-742b-4ed1-9fa1-79a24cd1a07e/1f657058-509e-4057-ad33-3e519f1d9672/inorganic_unit_01.txt)
(https://ppl-ai-file-upload.s3.amazonaws.com/web/direct-files/collection_99e4096c-742b-4ed1-9fa1-79a24cd1a07e/851d31c2-99cf-4f1d-964a-940ec8b03542/inorganic_unit_05.txt)
(https://ppl-ai-file-upload.s3.amazonaws.com/web/direct-files/collection_99e4096c-742b-4ed1-9fa1-79a24cd1a07e/d13e1942-f9f7-4189-9aa9-1f84857a7358/inorganic_unit_08.txt)
(https://ppl-ai-file-upload.s3.amazonaws.com/web/direct-files/collection_99e4096c-742b-4ed1-9fa1-79a24cd1a07e/5d502e9e-092b-46f4-8408-a3ef07ba2c84/inorganic_unit_10.txt)
(https://ppl-ai-file-upload.s3.amazonaws.com/web/direct-files/collection_99e4096c-742b-4ed1-9fa1-79a24cd1a07e/445593be-22b9-4e14-bfb3-8a947e2c083d/organic_unit_11.txt)
(https://ppl-ai-file-upload.s3.amazonaws.com/web/direct-files/collection_99e4096c-742b-4ed1-9fa1-79a24cd1a07e/05b8dcdd-1242-4c0d-93c3-7b80e9ac6fa7/physical_unit_13.txt)]]></text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Many covalent halides of p-block elements hydrolyze because the central atom can act as a Lewis acid toward water]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Correct!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[All halides hydrolyze completely and violently regardless of bonding type]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Hydrolysis is impossible for halides because halogen atoms prevent any reaction with water]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Hydrolysis depends only on the physical state (solid/liquid/gas), not on bonding or Lewis acidity]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
</quiz>
