<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<quiz>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text>Both XeF₂ and ICl₃ are</text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text>Both XeF₂ and ICl₃ are commonly explained using multi-center bonding ideas in addition to VSEPR; which statement best captures the shared bonding logic that helps rationalize their hypervalent electron counts?</text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text>The unit explicitly frames xenon fluorides and several interhalogens in terms of hypervalency and multi-center bonding, including the three-center four-electron model.  This delocalized-bond picture allows electron-rich descriptions without forcing all bonding into localized two-center bonds while still connecting to VSEPR-based shapes.  Treating d-orbital participation as the only explanation conflicts with the unit’s emphasis that bonding models exist alongside an explicit “d-orbital participation debate/current understanding.”  A purely ionic picture does not align with the unit’s focus on structural determination, bonding models, and spectroscopic characterization for these species.  A strict octet-only localized bonding view is inconsistent with the unit’s repeated treatment of “expanded octets/hypervalency” for noble-gas fluorides and interhalogens.</text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text>Both can be rationalized using three-center four-electron bonding involving a delocalized set of electrons over three atoms, consistent with “expanded octet” behavior.</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Correct!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>Both require true d-orbital covalent bonding as the only valid explanation for bonds beyond an octet.</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>Both must be purely ionic in the solid state, so any covalent bonding model is unnecessary.</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>Both strictly follow the octet rule with only localized two-center two-electron bonds on the central atom.</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text>A sample shows a single</text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text>A sample shows a single ¹⁹F NMR resonance for an interhalogen that is VSEPR-predicted to contain more than one distinct fluorine environment at a static structure; which inference is most defensible using the unit’s emphasis on variable-temperature NMR and structure determination?</text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text>The unit explicitly connects ¹⁹F NMR to xenon and interhalogen compounds and also highlights variable-temperature NMR studies as a way to interpret spectra when structures are not rigid.  If a static VSEPR picture predicts inequivalent fluorines, a single observed resonance can be rationalized by rapid interchange that makes fluorines equivalent on the measurement timescale.  Declaring VSEPR “invalid” overreaches, since the unit repeatedly uses extended VSEPR as a primary structure-prediction tool for these exact systems.  The inference about “must be a noble-gas oxide” is unrelated to the spectroscopy framing in the unit and incorrectly restricts NMR behavior to a compound class.  A single resonance does not uniquely imply linearity; it can also arise from symmetry or dynamic averaging in non-linear hypervalent systems discussed here.</text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text>The molecule is undergoing dynamic exchange that averages fluorine environments on the NMR timescale, and variable-temperature ¹⁹F NMR can test this by changing the exchange rate.</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Correct!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>VSEPR theory is invalid for interhalogens, so geometry cannot be inferred at all from electron counting.</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>The compound must be a noble-gas oxide, because only oxides give one NMR signal.</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>The single resonance proves the molecule is linear, because linear molecules always have one fluorine environment.</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text>CN⁻ is treated as a</text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text>CN⁻ is treated as a pseudohalide and also as a ligand with specific bonding character; which statement best links these ideas to explain why CN⁻ forms strong coordination complexes compared with many simple anions?</text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text>The unit explicitly lists CN⁻ under pseudohalogens and separately emphasizes its linear bonding description plus “π-donor and σ-acceptor character” and “coordination chemistry and complex formation.”  Connecting these points supports the idea that CN⁻ can participate in strong, structured bonding to metal centers rather than behaving as a purely ionic spectator.  Treating CN⁻ as noble-gas-like contradicts the unit’s placement of CN⁻ in a section focused on reactivity and coordination behavior.  The claim that pseudohalogens “never coordinate” conflicts with the unit’s explicit learning objective to analyze complex formation and coordination behavior of pseudohalides.  Hydrogen bonding is not the central explanation for CN⁻ complex formation in the unit’s framing, which focuses on electronic structure and coordination chemistry instead.</text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text>CN⁻ is linear with multiple bonding and is described here as having π-donor and σ-acceptor character, supporting strong, directional metal–ligand interactions and extensive complex formation.</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Correct!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>CN⁻ behaves like a noble gas atom because it has a filled valence shell, so it rarely binds to metals.</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>CN⁻ cannot act as a ligand because pseudohalogens only undergo displacement reactions and never coordinate.</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>CN⁻ forms strong complexes only due to hydrogen bonding, which dominates its chemistry in solution.</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text>Square-planar geometries are highlighted for</text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text>Square-planar geometries are highlighted for certain polyinterhalogen ions; which electron-counting/VSEPR-consistent statement best explains why ICl₄⁻ is square planar rather than tetrahedral?</text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text>The unit explicitly treats polyinterhalogen ions using “charge and electron counting methods” and emphasizes “square planar geometry and lone pairs” along with “VSEPR application with negative charge.”  Including the −1 charge in electron counting increases the central-atom electron pair count, making lone-pair effects sufficient to drive square-planar shapes for ions like ICl₄⁻.  Assuming all four-coordinate species are tetrahedral ignores the unit’s direct inclusion of square-planar polyinterhalogen ions and square-planar hypervalent systems.  The claim about iodine being unable to expand coordination number conflicts with the unit’s broader discussion of high coordination numbers in interhalogens and polyinterhalogen chemistry.  Assigning fixed 90° angles to chlorine is not a valid structural principle in this context; the unit’s structure determination relies on VSEPR, electron counting, and spectroscopy rather than “element-forced” angles.</text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text>Counting the negative charge in the VSEPR electron inventory yields an AX₄E₂ situation on iodine, giving an octahedral electron-pair arrangement with a square-planar molecular shape.</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Correct!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>ICl₄⁻ must be tetrahedral because all four-coordinate species are tetrahedral by default.</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>ICl₄⁻ is square planar only because iodine cannot expand its coordination number beyond 4.</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>ICl₄⁻ is square planar because chlorine always forces 90° bond angles in any compound.</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text>Xenon oxides (XeO₃, XeO₄) are</text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text>Xenon oxides (XeO₃, XeO₄) are presented as strong oxidizers with notable instability; which integrated explanation best matches the unit’s structure–property emphasis?</text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text>The unit explicitly links xenon oxides/oxyfluorides to oxidizing ability and also emphasizes instability and explosive decomposition patterns for XeO₃ and XeO₄.  Combining “high oxidation state” reasoning with structure–property relationships aligns with the unit’s focus on predicting reactivity from structure and comparing oxidizing/redox properties across classes.  Invoking xenon’s inertness as the reason for stability contradicts the unit’s central milestone that noble gases can form reactive compounds and the explicit oxidizing behavior assigned to xenon oxides.  The geometry assignments in the incorrect statement are reversed relative to the unit’s presentation (XeO₃ pyramidal; XeO₄ tetrahedral), and geometry alone is not sufficient to explain oxidizing power without oxidation-state/redox context.  Hydrogen bonding is not the driver emphasized for these inorganic oxidizers in the unit, which instead stresses bonding, oxidation states, and decomposition/reactivity patterns.
(https://ppl-ai-file-upload.s3.amazonaws.com/web/direct-files/collection_99e4096c-742b-4ed1-9fa1-79a24cd1a07e/26588078-225d-4384-895e-f69546b64bf1/inorganic_unit_03.txt)</text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text>High xenon oxidation states combined with structural/bonding features in oxygen-containing xenon compounds make them powerful oxidants, and their decomposition can be energetically favorable, contributing to instability and explosive tendencies.</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Correct!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>XeO₃ and XeO₄ are stable mainly because xenon is inert, so they cannot act as oxidizing agents.</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>XeO₃ is tetrahedral while XeO₄ is pyramidal, and this shape reversal explains all reactivity trends.</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>Their oxidizing behavior is unrelated to oxidation state and instead arises only from hydrogen bonding networks.</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text>The high chemical inertness of</text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text>The high chemical inertness of noble gases is most directly attributed to:</text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text>Noble gases have closed-shell electronic configurations, so there is little driving force to form bonds under ordinary conditions.  High ionization energy makes electron removal difficult, reinforcing inertness.  High electron affinity is not characteristic of noble gases, so it does not explain their behavior.  Low electronegativity does not imply easy oxidation for closed-shell atoms, and vacant d-orbitals are not the key reason for inertness.</text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text>A filled valence shell and high ionization energy in general</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Correct!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>Very high electron affinity values across the group</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>Very low electronegativity leading to easy oxidation</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>Presence of vacant d-orbitals that strongly attract electrons</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text>Xenon forms stable compounds more</text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text>Xenon forms stable compounds more readily than lighter noble gases primarily because xenon has:</text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text>Down Group 18, atomic size increases and ionization energy generally decreases, making xenon comparatively more reactive.  Greater polarizability and accessible oxidation states help xenon interact with very electronegative elements like fluorine.  Xenon does not have an empty valence shell, and noble gases do not typically form stable anions like Xe²⁻ under normal chemistry.  Xenon is not described as having the highest electronegativity; the key driver emphasized is ionization energy and related trends.</text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text>Lower ionization energy and larger, more polarizable electron cloud</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Correct!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>A completely empty valence shell</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>The highest electronegativity among noble gases</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>A natural tendency to exist as Xe²⁻ in solids</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text>The first widely recognized noble-gas</text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text>The first widely recognized noble-gas compound that initiated modern noble-gas chemistry was:</text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text>The first synthesis highlighted in the learning path is XePtF₆, marking the breakthrough that noble gases can form compounds.  Xenon oxides (like XeO₄) and krypton difluoride (KrF₂) are discussed as later or additional noble-gas compounds, not the initial landmark discovery.  IF₇ is an interhalogen compound and is not a noble-gas compound.</text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text>XePtF₆</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Correct!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>XeO₄</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>KrF₂</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>IF₇</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text>Using VSEPR theory, the molecular</text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text>Using VSEPR theory, the molecular geometry of XeF₂ is predicted to be:</text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text>XeF₂ is treated as having five electron pairs around xenon (two bonding pairs and three lone pairs), giving a trigonal-bipyramidal electron-pair arrangement.  Lone pairs occupy equatorial positions, leaving the two Xe–F bonds axial and producing a linear molecular shape.  Trigonal planar would require three bonding regions and no appropriate lone-pair arrangement for XeF₂ as presented here.  T-shaped and square planar correspond to different electron-pair counts/arrangements than XeF₂ in the learning path.</text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text>Linear</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Correct!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>Trigonal planar</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>T-shaped</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>Square planar</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text>The bonding in XeF₂ is</text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text>The bonding in XeF₂ is best described by which model?</text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text>XeF₂ is specifically associated with a three-center four-electron (3c–4e) bonding description in the learning path.  A fully ionic Xe²⁺ formulation is not the bonding model emphasized for xenon fluorides.  Localized Xe=F double bonds are not the standard description for XeF₂ bonding in this context.  Hydrogen bonding is irrelevant here because the compound contains no hydrogen and its key feature is hypervalent bonding.</text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text>Three-center four-electron (3c–4e) bonding</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Correct!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>Purely ionic bonding: Xe²⁺ and 2F⁻</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>A localized Xe=F double bond framework</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>A hydrogen-bonded polymeric chain model</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text>The geometry of XeF₄ is</text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text>The geometry of XeF₄ is:</text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text>XeF₄ is described as square planar, consistent with VSEPR treatment where lone pairs influence geometry.  Tetrahedral would require four bonding pairs and no lone-pair arrangement that matches XeF₄ as discussed.  Trigonal bipyramidal and seesaw shapes correspond to five electron domains and different lone-pair distributions than the XeF₄ case in the syllabus outline.</text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text>Square planar</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Correct!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>Tetrahedral</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>Trigonal bipyramidal</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>Seesaw</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text>XeF₆ is best described as</text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text>XeF₆ is best described as having which molecular geometry (typical description emphasized)?</text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text>XeF₆ is highlighted as having a distorted octahedral structure, with asymmetry attributed to lone-pair effects.  A perfectly symmetric octahedral structure is not the emphasized description for XeF₆ here.  Trigonal planar and linear geometries correspond to far fewer electron domains than present in XeF₆.</text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text>Distorted octahedral (asymmetric due to lone-pair effects)</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Correct!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>Perfect octahedral (fully symmetric)</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>Trigonal planar</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>Linear</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text>The molecular geometry of IF₇</text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text>The molecular geometry of IF₇ is:</text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text>IF₇ is presented under XY₇ interhalogens and is associated with a pentagonal bipyramidal geometry by VSEPR considerations.  Square planar is typical for certain 4-coordinate species (including some polyinterhalogen ions) rather than a 7-coordinate neutral interhalogen.  T-shaped corresponds to many XY₃ interhalogens like BrF₃, not IF₇.  Tetrahedral is characteristic of 4 electron domains, which does not apply to IF₇.</text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text>Pentagonal bipyramidal</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Correct!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>Square planar</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>T-shaped</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>Tetrahedral</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text>Which of the following is</text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text>Which of the following is a common pseudohalogen (pseudohalide) ion discussed in this unit?</text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text>CN⁻ is explicitly listed among common pseudohalogens/pseudohalides (along with SCN⁻, N₃⁻, OCN⁻, SeCN⁻).  Hydroxide, nitrate, and carbonate are not classified as pseudohalogens in the provided concept list.  The pseudohalogen idea here centers on halide-like behavior, which is specifically attributed to ions like CN⁻ and SCN⁻ in the unit.</text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text>CN⁻</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Correct!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>OH⁻</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>NO₃⁻</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>CO₃²⁻</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text>The geometry of the polyinterhalogen</text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text>The geometry of the polyinterhalogen ion BrF₄⁻ is:</text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text>BrF₄⁻ is listed among polyinterhalogen ions and is associated with square planar geometry in the unit’s polyinterhalogen section.  Tetrahedral would correspond to four bonding regions with no strong lone-pair-driven planarity as emphasized for these ions.  Trigonal planar and linear geometries do not match a four-fluoride coordination environment for BrF₄⁻ as presented.
(https://ppl-ai-file-upload.s3.amazonaws.com/web/direct-files/collection_99e4096c-742b-4ed1-9fa1-79a24cd1a07e/26588078-225d-4384-895e-f69546b64bf1/inorganic_unit_03.txt)</text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text>Square planar</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Correct!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>Tetrahedral</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>Trigonal planar</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>Linear</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text>In XeOF₄, the oxidation state</text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text>In XeOF₄, the oxidation state of xenon is:</text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text>Take F as −1 (four fluorines give −4) and O as −2, so xenon must be +6 to make the molecule neutral.  +4 would not balance the total ligand charge and would leave the molecule overall negative.  +8 is common for XeO₄ but is too high for a species containing four fluorides and one oxide as written.  +2 is inconsistent with xenon oxyfluoride chemistry emphasized alongside higher oxidation states.</text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>+4</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text>+6</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Correct!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>+8</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>+2</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text>The number of lone pairs</text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text>The number of lone pairs on the central atom in XeF₄, as inferred from its square planar geometry (VSEPR), is:</text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text>A square planar molecular shape for an AX₄E₂ species arises from an octahedral electron-pair arrangement with two lone pairs opposite each other.  With zero lone pairs, an AX₄ species would typically be tetrahedral rather than square planar.  With one lone pair, the expected shape would be a seesaw-type distortion for five electron domains rather than square planar.  Three lone pairs with four bonds would imply seven electron domains, which is not the standard VSEPR count used for XeF₄ in this unit.</text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>0</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>1</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text>2</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Correct!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>3</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text>For IF₅ (square pyramidal), how</text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text>For IF₅ (square pyramidal), how many distinct fluorine environments are expected in ¹⁹F NMR if the structure is rigid on the NMR timescale?</text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text>In a square pyramidal structure, one fluorine is axial while the four basal fluorines are symmetry-equivalent, giving two distinct sets.  A single environment would require all five fluorines to be equivalent, which is not consistent with square pyramidal geometry.  Three environments would imply further inequivalence among basal fluorines, which is not expected for the idealized structure used in VSEPR-based structure determination.  Five environments would require all fluorines to be inequivalent, which would contradict the symmetry implied by square pyramidal geometry.</text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>1</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text>2</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Correct!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>3</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>5</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text>BrF₃ is T-shaped by VSEPR</text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text>BrF₃ is T-shaped by VSEPR; the number of lone pairs on bromine in BrF₃ is:</text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text>A T-shaped molecule corresponds to AX₃E₂ with five electron domains (trigonal bipyramidal electron arrangement) and two lone pairs occupying equatorial positions.  With zero lone pairs, three bonds would typically give trigonal planar geometry.  With one lone pair and three bonds, a seesaw geometry is more consistent than a T-shape.  With three lone pairs and three bonds, six electron domains would be implied and the structure would not match the T-shaped description used for XY₃ interhalogens here.</text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>0</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>1</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text>2</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Correct!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>3</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text>Which interhalogen is expected to</text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text>Which interhalogen is expected to have the greatest steric effect from lone pairs on the central halogen when comparing BrF₃ (T-shaped), IF₅ (square pyramidal), and IF₇ (pentagonal bipyramidal)?</text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text>BrF₃ (AX₃E₂) has two lone pairs, which strongly influence geometry and bond angles in the VSEPR picture used for interhalogens.  IF₅ (AX₅E) has only one lone pair, so lone-pair effects are present but typically less dominating than with two lone pairs.  IF₇ is commonly treated as having no lone pairs on iodine in the simple VSEPR count for a pentagonal bipyramidal structure.  The lone-pair counts therefore differ across these three species.</text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text>BrF₃</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Correct!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>IF₅</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>IF₇</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>All have the same lone-pair count</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text>Using electron-counting logic from VSEPR-based</text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text>Using electron-counting logic from VSEPR-based structure determination, which species is most consistent with a square planar geometry among the following?</text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text>XeF₄ is explicitly associated with square planar geometry and lone-pair-controlled structure in this unit.  IF₇ is associated with pentagonal bipyramidal geometry rather than square planar.  XeF₂ is linear under the VSEPR model used for noble gas fluorides.  IF₅ is square pyramidal, which differs from square planar by having an additional axial bond.</text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text>XeF₄</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Correct!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>IF₇</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>XeF₂</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>IF₅</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text>The stability trend among xenon</text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text>The stability trend among xenon fluorides stated in this unit is XeF₂ &gt; XeF₄ &gt; XeF₆; which reasoning best aligns with correlating structure and lone-pair effects?</text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text>The unit highlights a stability trend and also emphasizes lone-pair-driven distortions and reactivity patterns in xenon fluorides, which qualitatively supports decreasing stability with higher fluorination in that sequence.  XeF₆ is discussed with lone-pair effects and asymmetry, so describing it as having no lone pairs conflicts with the structural discussion.  Hypervalency alone does not make XeF₂ least stable here because XeF₂ is explicitly placed as the most stable in the stated trend.  Square planarity of XeF₄ is a geometry outcome and is not presented as the primary reason it would be least stable compared to XeF₆ in this trend.</text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text>Greater fluorine content increases polarization and makes higher fluorides thermally less stable in the trend given.</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Correct!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>XeF₆ has no lone pairs, so it is least stable.</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>XeF₂ is least stable because it is hypervalent.</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>XeF₄ is least stable because it is square planar.</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text>Consider ICl₄⁻ (a polyinterhalogen ion)</text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text>Consider ICl₄⁻ (a polyinterhalogen ion). The oxidation state of iodine in ICl₄⁻ is:</text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text>Assign each chlorine as −1; four chlorines contribute −4 total, and the overall ion charge is −1, so iodine must be +3 to satisfy charge balance.  +1 would yield an overall charge of −3, not −1.  +5 would yield an overall charge of +1, not −1.  A negative oxidation state on iodine would make the total charge far more negative than −1 for four chloride ligands.</text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>+1</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text>+3</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Correct!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>+5</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>−3</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text>SCN⁻ is often described as</text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text>SCN⁻ is often described as ambidentate in coordination chemistry; which donor-atom pair best represents this behavior?</text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text>The unit explicitly ties thiocyanate (SCN⁻) to ambidentate behavior and coordination isomerism, which arises from its ability to bind through different atoms.  Binding through sulfur versus nitrogen is the classic ambidentate choice for SCN⁻, consistent with the “ambidentate behavior” section.  Carbon/oxygen binding corresponds more to ions like OCN⁻/NCO⁻ patterns rather than SCN⁻ as emphasized here.  Fluorine/chlorine and oxygen/hydrogen are not the donor-atom options relevant to SCN⁻ ambidentate coordination.</text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text>Sulfur or nitrogen</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Correct!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>Carbon or oxygen</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>Fluorine or chlorine</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>Oxygen or hydrogen</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text>Which statement best connects why</text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text>Which statement best connects why fluorine forms the largest variety of interhalogen compounds to periodic properties emphasized in this unit?</text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text>The unit includes “Why fluorine forms most interhalogen compounds” under interhalogen classification and ties interhalogen formation to halogen periodic trends.  High electronegativity and small size support strong bonding and stabilization of a wide range of interhalogens relative to other halogen combinations.  Formation of F⁺ is not a standard driver for interhalogen formation trends discussed under halogen fundamentals.  High polarizability is more characteristic of heavier halogens, and describing fluorine as metallic is chemically incorrect for the halogen family context used here.
(https://ppl-ai-file-upload.s3.amazonaws.com/web/direct-files/collection_99e4096c-742b-4ed1-9fa1-79a24cd1a07e/26588078-225d-4384-895e-f69546b64bf1/inorganic_unit_03.txt)</text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text>Fluorine’s very high electronegativity and small size favor strong X–F bonding across many partners.</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Correct!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>Fluorine has the lowest ionization energy among halogens, so it readily becomes F⁺.</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>Fluorine is highly polarizable, so it stabilizes large polyhalide clusters best.</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>Fluorine is metallic in nature, so it forms intermetallic interhalogens easily.</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
</quiz>
