<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<quiz>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text>The later lanthanides often show</text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text>The later lanthanides often show chemical similarity to certain 4d and 5d transition metals in their ionic radii and coordination behaviour. Which combination best rationalises this similarity?</text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text>The strong lanthanide contraction arises because 4f electrons shield the increasing nuclear charge poorly, so the effective nuclear charge felt by outer electrons increases significantly from La to Lu.  This leads to a pronounced, nearly monotonic decrease in both atomic and ionic radii across the lanthanide series, especially for Ln³⁺ ions.  As a result, later lanthanides (such as Tb–Lu) attain radii comparable to those of certain 4d and 5d transition metals in similar oxidation states, giving rise to similarities in coordination numbers and ligand preferences.  Options invoking weak contraction, strong shielding, loss of 4f electrons, or a universal +2 oxidation state contradict the described physical basis and observed +3-dominated chemistry.
***</text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text>Strong lanthanide contraction and poor 4f shielding</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Correct!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>Weak lanthanide contraction and strong 4f shielding</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>Absence of 4f electrons in later lanthanides</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>Dominant +2 oxidation state for all later lanthanides</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text>Consider two isostructural complexes: [Nd(H₂O)₉]³⁺</text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text>Consider two isostructural complexes: [Nd(H₂O)₉]³⁺ and [Lu(H₂O)₈]³⁺ in aqueous solution. Which integrated explanation best accounts for the difference in coordination number and metal–oxygen bond distances?</text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text>Across the lanthanide series, the lanthanide contraction steadily decreases the ionic radii of Ln³⁺ ions due to poor 4f shielding and rising effective nuclear charge.  Smaller later ions such as Lu³⁺ accommodate fewer ligands in the first coordination sphere, which favours lower coordination numbers (e.g., 8 vs 9 for larger early ions like Nd³⁺) and shorter metal–oxygen distances.  The dominant bonding remains largely ionic with limited 4f covalency, so a dramatic covalency increase alone does not primarily govern coordination-number changes.  There is no oxidation-state change from Nd³⁺ to Lu³⁺, and Lu³⁺ retains a 4f¹⁴ configuration rather than losing all 4f character for enhanced 6s bonding.
***</text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>Increase in 4f covalency from Nd to Lu with negligible size change</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text>Lanthanide contraction reducing ionic radius and favouring lower coordination for Lu³⁺</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Correct!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>Complete loss of 4f electrons in Lu³⁺ causing stronger 6s bonding</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>Change from +3 to +4 oxidation state from Nd to Lu</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text>A spectroscopist compares the electronic</text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text>A spectroscopist compares the electronic spectra of a Ln³⁺ aqua complex and an isoelectronic An³⁺ complex with the same ligand set. The actinide complex shows broader, more intense bands extending into the visible, while the lanthanide complex exhibits sharp, weak f–f lines. Which integrated factor best explains this contrast?</text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text>The 5f orbitals in actinides are less shielded and more radially extended than the 4f orbitals in lanthanides, so they overlap more effectively with ligand orbitals and give greater metal–ligand covalency.  This enhanced interaction favours intense ligand-to-metal and metal-to-ligand charge-transfer (CT) bands that are broad and often dominate actinide spectra.  In lanthanides, 4f orbitals are more core-like and shielded by 5s and 5p shells, leading to weak ligand field effects and narrow, Laporte-forbidden f–f transitions with low intensity.  Statements denying f–f transitions in actinides or reversing the relative diffuseness of 4f vs 5f orbitals ignore the central role of 5f–ligand overlap in actinide spectral behaviour, and spin–orbit coupling is important in both series rather than negligible in actinides.
***</text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>Actinides lack f–f transitions and show only intra-ligand bands</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text>5f orbitals in actinides are more radially extended, enhancing covalency and charge-transfer transitions</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Correct!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>4f orbitals in lanthanides are more diffuse, causing strong charge-transfer bands</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>Spin–orbit coupling is negligible in actinides but dominant in lanthanides</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text>A chemist wants to separate</text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text>A chemist wants to separate Eu and Gd from a mixed lanthanide chloride solution using a combination of redox chemistry and ion-exchange chromatography. Which conceptual strategy most effectively exploits their electronic structures and magnetic properties?</text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text>Eu readily forms a stable +2 oxidation state (Eu²⁺) associated with a half-filled 4f⁷ configuration, whereas Gd remains most stable as Gd³⁺, also with a 4f⁷ configuration but different charge and radius.  Reducing Eu³⁺ to Eu²⁺ changes its charge, ionic size, and complexation behaviour relative to Gd³⁺, which can be exploited in ion-exchange chromatography or solvent extraction for efficient separation.  Keeping both ions in +3 state leaves them very similar in radius and chemistry due to the lanthanide contraction, making separation far more difficult.  Oxidation to +4 is not generally favourable for these specific elements, and relying only on magnetic differences without altering charge and coordination chemistry is not the standard industrial or laboratory strategy described for lanthanide separations.
***</text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>Oxidise both to +4 and separate based on identical f-electron counts</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text>Reduce Eu³⁺ to Eu²⁺ while keeping Gd as Gd³⁺, then separate using different complexation and ionic sizes</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Correct!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>Oxidise Gd³⁺ to Gd⁴⁺ while keeping Eu³⁺ unchanged, then rely only on their different magnetic moments</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>Keep both in +3 state and depend solely on their similar ionic radii in a single ion-exchange step</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text>For a lanthanide ion with</text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text>For a lanthanide ion with a 4f⁹ configuration in the +3 oxidation state, application of Hund’s rules and LS coupling gives a ground state with significant orbital angular momentum and nonzero J. How does this influence both its magnetic moment and the way crystal fields perturb its electronic spectrum compared to a 4f⁷ Ln³⁺ ion?</text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text>In LS coupling, a 4f⁷ configuration such as Gd³⁺ has L ≈ 0 and a ground state with J = S, so its magnetic moment is close to the spin-only value and crystal-field perturbations of its f–f manifold are comparatively modest.  By contrast, a 4f⁹ Ln³⁺ ion possesses nonzero L and a ground-state term with significant total J, giving a magnetic moment that includes substantial orbital contribution via the appropriate J-dependent formula rather than simple spin-only.  Nonzero L also makes the ion more sensitive to crystal-field splitting, so its f–f transitions show more pronounced Stark components and fine structure than in the L ≈ 0 case.  Options that claim identical L for both ions or that assign stronger orbital effects to the half-filled 4f⁷ configuration contradict the LS-coupling and Hund’s-rule description used for lanthanide spectra and magnetism.
(https://ppl-ai-file-upload.s3.amazonaws.com/web/direct-files/collection_99e4096c-742b-4ed1-9fa1-79a24cd1a07e/8e891cd7-93c2-45ab-b55b-f9bb7cff4b54/inorganic_unit_06.txt)</text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>The 4f⁹ ion has purely spin-only behaviour and is insensitive to crystal fields, unlike 4f⁷</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>Both ions have L ≈ 0, so crystal-field splitting and magnetic moments are identical</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text>The 4f⁹ ion has larger orbital contribution to μeff and shows more pronounced crystal-field-induced Stark splitting of f–f levels</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Correct!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>The 4f⁷ ion always has a larger orbital contribution and stronger crystal-field effects than 4f⁹</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text>The lanthanide elements in the</text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text>The lanthanide elements in the periodic table are characterized by the progressive filling of which subshell?</text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text>Lanthanides (La–Lu) are f-block elements where the 4f subshell is progressively filled across the series. Their general electronic configuration is [Xe]4f^n where n varies from 0 to 14. The 3d subshell is filled in first-row transition metals. The 5d subshell is involved in third-row transition elements. The 5f subshell is progressively filled in actinides, not lanthanides.
***</text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>3d subshell</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text>4f subshell</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Correct!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>5d subshell</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>5f subshell</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text>What is the most common</text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text>What is the most common oxidation state exhibited by lanthanide elements in their compounds?</text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text>The dominant oxidation state for lanthanides is +3, which results from the loss of two 6s electrons and one 4f or 5d electron. This +3 state is remarkably stable across the entire lanthanide series. While +2 and +4 states exist for certain lanthanides like europium (+2) and cerium (+4), these are exceptions rather than the rule. The +5 oxidation state is not observed in lanthanides under normal conditions.
***</text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>+2</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text>+3</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Correct!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>+4</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>+5</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text>The lanthanide contraction refers to</text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text>The lanthanide contraction refers to which observed trend across the lanthanide series?</text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text>Lanthanide contraction is the steady decrease in atomic and ionic radii across the lanthanide series from lanthanum to lutetium. This contraction occurs because 4f electrons shield the nuclear charge poorly, leading to a greater effective nuclear charge experienced by outer electrons as the atomic number increases. This phenomenon has important consequences for coordination chemistry and separation techniques. The contraction does not refer to changes in oxidation state or a systematic decrease in magnetic moment.
***</text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>Increase in atomic radius from La to Lu</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text>Steady decrease in atomic and ionic radii from La to Lu</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Correct!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>Increase in oxidation state from La to Lu</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>Decrease in magnetic moment from La to Lu</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text>Which of the following minerals</text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text>Which of the following minerals is a primary ore for the extraction of lanthanides?</text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text>Monazite is a phosphate mineral that serves as one of the primary ores for lanthanide extraction, along with bastnasite. Monazite typically contains lanthanides along with thorium. Chalcopyrite is a copper-iron sulfide mineral used for copper extraction. Bauxite is the primary ore for aluminum production. Galena is a lead sulfide mineral used for lead extraction.
***</text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>Chalcopyrite</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text>Monazite</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Correct!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>Bauxite</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>Galena</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text>The actinide series begins with</text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text>The actinide series begins with actinium and ends with which element?</text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text>The actinide series consists of 15 elements from actinium (Ac, atomic number 89) to lawrencium (Lr, atomic number 103). These are f-block elements where the 5f subshell is progressively filled. Uranium, plutonium, and curium are all actinides but are located earlier in the series. Lawrencium is the last member of the actinide series, after which begins the 6d block.
***</text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>Uranium</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>Plutonium</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>Curium</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text>Lawrencium</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Correct!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text>Why do lanthanide complexes exhibit</text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text>Why do lanthanide complexes exhibit weak absorption bands in their electronic spectra?</text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text>Lanthanide complexes show weak absorption bands because f–f electronic transitions are Laporte forbidden. The Laporte selection rule states that transitions between orbitals of the same parity are forbidden, and since f orbitals have defined parity, f–f transitions have very low intensity. Additionally, 4f electrons are well-shielded by outer electron shells, further reducing ligand field effects. The statement about having no d electrons is irrelevant to f–f transition intensity. Lanthanides do form stable complexes, and their 4f orbitals are not completely filled except in Lu³⁺.
***</text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>Lanthanides have no d electrons</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text>The f–f transitions are Laporte forbidden</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Correct!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>Lanthanide ions do not form complexes</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>The 4f orbitals are completely filled</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text>The PUREX process is primarily</text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text>The PUREX process is primarily used for the extraction and purification of which actinide element?</text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text>PUREX (Plutonium–Uranium Redox Extraction) is an industrial solvent extraction process primarily designed for the separation and purification of plutonium and uranium from spent nuclear fuel. The process relies on selective extraction using tributyl phosphate in a hydrocarbon solvent. While thorium can be extracted from monazite using other methods, it is not the target of PUREX. Americium and curium require more specialized separation techniques beyond standard PUREX processing.
***</text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>Thorium</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text>Plutonium</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Correct!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>Americium</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>Curium</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text>Which separation technique has historically</text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text>Which separation technique has historically been used for the isolation of individual lanthanides based on slight solubility differences?</text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text>Fractional crystallization of lanthanide double salts (such as double sulfates or double nitrates) was historically employed to separate individual lanthanides based on their slight differences in solubility. This tedious method required hundreds of recrystallization steps due to the chemical similarity of lanthanides. Modern methods like ion-exchange chromatography and solvent extraction are now preferred. Distillation is unsuitable for separating lanthanide salts. Simple filtration cannot differentiate between dissolved lanthanide ions. Magnetic separation is not effective for lanthanide chemical separation.
***</text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>Distillation</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>Filtration</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text>Fractional crystallization</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Correct!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>Magnetic separation</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text>In actinides, the oxidation states</text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text>In actinides, the oxidation states are more variable compared to lanthanides. Which range of oxidation states is observed in actinides?</text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text>Actinides exhibit highly variable oxidation states ranging from +2 to +7, unlike lanthanides which predominantly show +3. This variability arises because 5f electrons in actinides are less tightly held and can participate in bonding more readily than 4f electrons in lanthanides. For example, uranium can exist in +3, +4, +5, and +6 states, while plutonium can exhibit +3 through +7 oxidation states. Actinides do not commonly exhibit +8 oxidation states under normal chemical conditions.
***</text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>+1 to +3</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text>+2 to +7</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Correct!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>+3 to +5</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>+4 to +8</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text>The calculation of magnetic moments</text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text>The calculation of magnetic moments for lanthanide ions requires consideration of which coupling scheme due to strong spin–orbit interactions?</text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text>Russell–Saunders (LS) coupling is used to derive term symbols and calculate magnetic moments for lanthanide ions because of significant spin–orbit coupling in these heavy elements. This coupling scheme combines individual spin and orbital angular momenta to give total S and L quantum numbers, which then couple to form the total angular momentum J. The magnetic moment formula incorporates the J quantum number. Jahn-Teller coupling refers to geometric distortion in degenerate electronic states. Molecular orbital coupling and ionic coupling are not standard coupling schemes for calculating lanthanide magnetic moments.
---
(https://ppl-ai-file-upload.s3.amazonaws.com/web/direct-files/collection_99e4096c-742b-4ed1-9fa1-79a24cd1a07e/8e891cd7-93c2-45ab-b55b-f9bb7cff4b54/inorganic_unit_06.txt)</text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>Jahn-Teller coupling</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text>Russell–Saunders (LS) coupling</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Correct!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>Molecular orbital coupling</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>Ionic coupling</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text>Arrange the following Ln3+ ions</text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text>Arrange the following Ln3+ ions in decreasing ionic radius (assume the same coordination number): La3+, Nd3+, Gd3+, Lu3+.</text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text>Across La to Lu, radii decrease steadily due to the lanthanide contraction arising from poor 4f shielding.  This contraction makes earlier lanthanides larger and later lanthanides smaller when compared at the same charge and coordination number.  The trend therefore gives La3+ as the largest and Lu3+ as the smallest, with intermediate ions like Nd3+ and Gd3+ falling in between.  Statements implying an increase across the series or non-monotonic changes contradict the established contraction trend.
***</text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text>La3+ &gt; Nd3+ &gt; Gd3+ &gt; Lu3+</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Correct!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>La3+ &gt; Gd3+ &gt; Nd3+ &gt; Lu3+</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>Lu3+ &gt; Gd3+ &gt; Nd3+ &gt; La3+</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>Nd3+ &gt; La3+ &gt; Gd3+ &gt; Lu3+</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text>In aqueous coordination chemistry, how</text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text>In aqueous coordination chemistry, how does coordination number typically change from early to late Ln3+ ions as a consequence of lanthanide contraction?</text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text>The decreasing ionic size across the lanthanide series leads to a gradual reduction in preferred coordination numbers for Ln3+ in many ligand environments.  Early, larger Ln3+ ions accommodate higher coordination (often 9–10), whereas later, smaller Ln3+ ions more commonly adopt 8–9.  This behavior reflects the impact of the lanthanide contraction on steric crowding and metal–ligand packing around the ion.  Claims of increasing or constant coordination number miss the size-driven steric rationale central to this trend.
***</text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>Increases from ~8 to ~10</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text>Decreases from ~9–10 to ~8–9</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Correct!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>Remains constant at 6</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>Becomes unpredictable with no trend</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text>Which single change most directly</text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text>Which single change most directly enhances the intensity of f–f bands in lanthanide complexes?</text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text>f–f transitions are parity-forbidden by the Laporte rule, so the presence of an inversion center suppresses intensity.  Lowering symmetry to remove inversion symmetry partially relaxes the selection rule via vibronic coupling, increasing band intensity.  Changes that retain or increase centrosymmetry will not strengthen these transitions, and simple dilution does not alter intrinsic transition probabilities.  Ligand hardness alone does not guarantee symmetry changes required to lift parity restrictions significantly.
***</text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>Introducing an inversion center at the metal</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text>Lowering site symmetry to remove inversion symmetry</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Correct!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>Replacing hard ligands with harder ligands only</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>Diluting the complex to reduce concentration effects</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text>Which actinide spectral feature is</text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text>Which actinide spectral feature is typically more intense and broader than f–f transitions?</text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text>Actinide spectra commonly display intense, broad charge-transfer (CT) bands that overshadow weak f–f transitions.  The higher covalency and variable oxidation states in actinides favor LMCT/MLCT processes with large oscillator strengths.  In contrast, f–f transitions remain relatively weak due to parity and selection-rule constraints, even with spin–orbit coupling.  d–d and intra-ligand bands are not the defining intense features for f-element complexes in this context.
***</text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>Spin-forbidden f–f bands</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>d–d transitions</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text>Charge-transfer bands</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Correct!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>Intra-ligand π–π* bands</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text>For U in different oxidation</text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text>For U in different oxidation states, which state is most likely to show the strongest CT character in its electronic spectrum under comparable ligand environments?</text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text>Increasing metal oxidation state typically lowers metal-centered orbital energies and enhances ligand-to-metal CT likelihood and intensity.  In actinides, higher oxidation states like U(VI) often exhibit strong CT bands compared with lower states such as U(III) or U(IV).  The file emphasizes that actinide spectra include both f–f and CT features, with CT transitions being especially intense.  Options favoring lower oxidation states overlook the general trend of increasing CT prominence with higher oxidation state.
***</text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>U(III)</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>U(IV)</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>U(V)</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text>U(VI)</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Correct!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text>Which technique exploits small differences</text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text>Which technique exploits small differences in complex formation and exchange equilibria to separate adjacent lanthanides efficiently at laboratory scale?</text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text>Ion-exchange chromatography is a classic high-resolution method for separating adjacent lanthanides that differ subtly in complexation behavior.  It leverages differential affinities of Ln3+–ligand species for the resin and eluent gradients to resolve closely similar ions.  Filtration cannot separate ions in solution, and distillation is inapplicable to nonvolatile salts.  Electrolysis does not selectively resolve closely similar trivalent f-element cations under standard conditions.
***</text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>Simple filtration</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>Distillation</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text>Ion-exchange chromatography</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Correct!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>Electrolysis</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text>Which process is used at</text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text>Which process is used at industrial scale to separate and purify U and Pu from spent nuclear fuel?</text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text>The PUREX (Plutonium–Uranium Redox Extraction) process is a solvent extraction method designed to co-extract and then separate U and Pu from irradiated fuel.  It employs selective complexation in tributyl phosphate phases coupled with redox control to partition actinides.  The other listed processes are not applicable to nuclear-fuel reprocessing and do not address U/Pu separations.  This aligns with the learning objective on industrial actinide separations.
***</text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>Mond process</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text>PUREX process</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Correct!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>Zone refining</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>Kroll process</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text>Among the following ions, which</text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text>Among the following ions, which is expected to have an effective magnetic moment closest to 7.9 BM?</text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text>For Gd3+ (4f7), L ≈ 0 and J = S = 7/2, giving μeff ≈ gJ√[J(J+1)] ≈ 2√[7/2·9/2] ≈ 7.94 BM.  Lanthanide magnetic moments must include spin–orbit coupling via LS coupling and Hund’s rules, not just spin-only estimates.  Ce3+ (4f1), Eu3+ (4f6), and Yb3+ (4f13) yield smaller μeff values due to nonzero L and differing J.  Recognizing L = 0 for half-filled 4f7 rationalizes why Gd3+ reaches the maximum typical μeff among Ln3+.
***</text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>Ce3+</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text>Gd3+</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Correct!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>Eu3+</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>Yb3+</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text>Which statement best compares magnetism</text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text>Which statement best compares magnetism in actinides vs lanthanides?</text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text>Actinide 5f orbitals are more spatially extended and interact more strongly with ligands, increasing covalency and crystal-field effects.  These factors produce larger deviations from simple spin-only predictions and more complex temperature dependencies.  Lanthanides exhibit strong spin–orbit coupling but 4f orbitals are more shielded, giving comparatively modest covalency.  Statements suggesting spin-only behavior or negligible orbital contributions contradict the emphasized role of spin–orbit and orbital terms.
***</text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>Actinides follow spin-only moments more closely than lanthanides.</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text>Actinides show greater deviations due to stronger 5f–ligand interactions and covalency.</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Correct!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>Both series strictly obey Curie law with negligible orbital effects.</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>Lanthanides show larger deviations because 4f orbitals are more diffuse.</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text>In solvent extraction-based separation of</text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text>In solvent extraction-based separation of adjacent lanthanides, which adjustment generally increases selectivity between two neighboring Ln3+ ions?</text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text>Solvent extraction resolves neighboring lanthanides by exploiting slight differences in complex stability and distribution ratios under tailored extractant and acidity conditions.  Optimizing ligand type and phase composition magnifies separation factors without requiring large intrinsic chemical differences.  Adjustments that do not change coordination equilibria (inert electrolyte, pure thermal changes, or absence of complexants) provide little selectivity.  This aligns with the emphasis on solvent extraction as a core separation method for lanthanides.
(https://ppl-ai-file-upload.s3.amazonaws.com/web/direct-files/collection_99e4096c-742b-4ed1-9fa1-79a24cd1a07e/8e891cd7-93c2-45ab-b55b-f9bb7cff4b54/inorganic_unit_06.txt)</text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text>Using an extractant/conditions that amplify small differences in complex stability</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Correct!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>Saturating the aqueous phase with inert electrolyte only</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>Increasing temperature without changing ligand chemistry</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text>Removing all complexing agents from both phases</text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text>Wrong!</text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
</quiz>
