<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<quiz>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text><![CDATA[A chemist wants a ring]]></text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[A chemist wants a ring that is strongly activated toward EAS at the α-position, yet has a heteroatom lone pair that is not readily protonated under mildly acidic conditions. Which choice best fits both constraints?]]></text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[α-Substitution (2-position) is characteristic for EAS in five-membered heteroaromatics because the α-σ-complex is better resonance-stabilized than the β-σ-complex.  Among furan, pyrrole, and thiophene, thiophene is typically EAS-active at α while being less prone than pyrrole to strong acid-base complications at the heteroatom, aligning with the unit’s comparative aromaticity/stability and substitution-pattern focus.  Pyrrole is strongly EAS-activated, but its nitrogen behavior (lone pair in the aromatic sextet, sensitivity in acid and N-reactivity) makes it less aligned with the “not readily protonated under mildly acidic conditions” constraint compared with a non-nitrogen heterocycle.  Pyridine fails the EAS-activation requirement because it is electron-poor and resists EAS due to nitrogen withdrawal.]]></text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Pyrrole]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Furan]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Thiophene]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Correct!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Pyridine]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text><![CDATA[A student claims: “Pyridine is]]></text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[A student claims: “Pyridine is less reactive toward EAS than benzene, but more reactive toward NAS than benzene; both effects originate from the same electronic feature.” Which option best captures the correct reasoning?]]></text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Pyridine’s ring nitrogen makes the ring electron-poor, which raises the barrier for EAS because σ-complex formation is cationic and is disfavored when electron density is low and when resonance forms place positive charge unfavorably near nitrogen.  The same electron-poor character can facilitate nucleophilic addition steps in NAS at favored positions (notably 2 and 4) because the intermediate anionic σ-complex can be better accommodated in an electron-deficient heteroaromatic framework.  Antiaromaticity is not the issue because pyridine is a 6π aromatic system, and nitrogen is not a net resonance donor into the ring π system as in pyrrole.]]></text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[True; ring nitrogen withdraws electron density, destabilizing cationic σ-complex (EAS) but stabilizing anionic σ-complex (NAS) at key positions]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Correct!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[True; pyridine is antiaromatic, so it avoids EAS but undergoes NAS to regain aromaticity]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[False; pyridine is less reactive than benzene in both EAS and NAS because aromatic rings never do NAS]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[False; pyridine is more reactive than benzene in EAS because nitrogen donates its lone pair to the ring]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text><![CDATA[In indole, electrophilic substitution is]]></text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[In indole, electrophilic substitution is often observed at C-3, whereas in pyridine, EAS is strongly disfavored and when it occurs it follows distinct regioselectivity. Which combined statement best explains these contrasting behaviors using aromatic stabilization arguments?]]></text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Indole’s fused π system allows formation of a particularly stabilized σ-complex upon C-3 attack, which is why C-3 is a dominant EAS site in the unit’s indole reactivity focus.  Pyridine’s ring nitrogen withdraws electron density and makes EAS difficult, consistent with the unit’s explicit emphasis on “why pyridine resists electrophilic aromatic substitution” and regioselectivity considerations.  Options that invert lone-pair participation (pyridine vs pyrrole-like systems) or reduce the effect to sterics contradict the electronic/aromaticity framework used to rationalize these outcomes.]]></text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Indole reacts at C-3 because attack there gives a highly resonance-stabilized σ-complex, while pyridine resists EAS because nitrogen withdraws electron density and destabilizes σ-complex formation]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Correct!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Indole reacts at C-3 because it is non-aromatic at that carbon, while pyridine is non-aromatic overall]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Indole reacts at C-3 because nitrogen’s lone pair is not in the aromatic sextet, while pyridine resists EAS because its lone pair is in the sextet]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Indole reacts at C-3 mainly due to steric hindrance at C-2, while pyridine resists EAS due to steric hindrance at all ring positions]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text><![CDATA[A synthetic planner must choose]]></text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[A synthetic planner must choose between quinoline and isoquinoline as a substrate where changing the position of nitrogen is intended to change substitution regiochemistry without changing overall aromatic character. Which statement is most defensible?]]></text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Quinoline and isoquinoline are highlighted as fused benzopyridine systems whose key distinction is the position of the ring nitrogen, and this positional change is used to rationalize different substitution patterns.  Both remain aromatic fused heterocycles; the design lever is electron distribution and directing effects, not a change from aromatic to non-aromatic.  They do not differ in nitrogen count, and “identical electron distribution” would contradict the unit’s emphasis on comparative analysis and different regiochemical outcomes.]]></text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Quinoline and isoquinoline are position isomers; shifting the ring nitrogen alters electron distribution and hence regioselectivity while keeping both aromatic]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Correct!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Quinoline is aromatic but isoquinoline is not, so nitrogen position changes aromaticity rather than regiochemistry]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Both have identical electron distribution because both are benzopyridines, so regiochemistry cannot change]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Regiochemistry changes only because isoquinoline has an extra nitrogen relative to quinoline]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text><![CDATA[A reaction sequence aims to]]></text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[A reaction sequence aims to “toggle” pyridine’s reactivity by a reversible redox modification at nitrogen to enable ring functionalization, then return to pyridine. Which strategic intermediate best fits this logic?]]></text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[The unit explicitly includes N-oxide formation and “activation via N-oxidation” under pyridine oxidation/reactivity, matching a redox-based, nitrogen-centered modification strategy used to alter substitution behavior and then revert.  Piperidine formation is a reduction that removes aromaticity, so it is not a simple “toggle” for aromatic substitution planning in the same framework.  Pyridinium ylides and quinolinium salts represent different reactivity manifolds and are not the canonical redox-toggle intermediate emphasized here compared with N-oxides.
(https://ppl-ai-file-upload.s3.amazonaws.com/web/direct-files/collection_99e4096c-742b-4ed1-9fa1-79a24cd1a07e/37bed375-4faf-4477-a010-e72ec0280345/organic_unit_10.txt)]]></text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Pyridine N-oxide]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Correct!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Pyridinium ylide]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Piperidine (fully hydrogenated)]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[A bicyclic quinolinium salt]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
</quiz>
