<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<quiz>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text><![CDATA[A solvolysis substrate can form]]></text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[A solvolysis substrate can form either a classical tertiary carbocation or a bridged (non-classical) carbocation through neighboring group participation. Which observation most strongly supports **anchimeric assistance** as the dominant pathway?]]></text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Anchimeric assistance (neighboring group participation) stabilizes developing positive charge by forming a bridged intermediate, often causing strong rate acceleration and altered stereochemical outcomes (commonly higher retention or reduced racemization compared with a fully free classical carbocation). A first-order rate law is consistent with many SN1-like ionizations and is not diagnostic; racemization is typical for classical SN1 and does not support strong neighboring participation; peroxide/radical-trap effects diagnose radical pathways, not cationic neighboring group participation.]]></text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[First-order rate law is observed.]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Product mixture shows racemization at the reacting center.]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Rate acceleration occurs along with predominant substitution giving retention-like stereochemical outcome compared to normal SN1 expectations.]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Correct!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Reaction requires peroxide initiator and shows inhibition by radical traps.]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text><![CDATA[Consider a rearrangement-prone carbocation that]]></text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Consider a rearrangement-prone carbocation that can undergo either a 1,2-hydride shift or a 1,2-alkyl shift. Which mechanistic criterion most reliably predicts which group migrates in a Wagner–Meerwein rearrangement?]]></text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Wagner–Meerwein rearrangements are driven by formation of a more stable carbocation (via resonance and/or hyperconjugation), so the preferred migrating group is the one that produces the more stabilized cationic center after the 1,2-shift. Bond dissociation energy is not the controlling metric because migration is not simple homolysis; strong −I groups typically destabilize carbocations; transition states are not identical because the developing cation stability differs.]]></text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[The group with the lowest bond dissociation energy migrates.]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[The group that leads to the most stabilized carbocation after migration migrates preferentially.]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Correct!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[The group with the strongest −I effect migrates first.]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Migration is random because both shifts proceed through identical transition states.]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text><![CDATA[A substrate undergoes rearrangement under]]></text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[A substrate undergoes rearrangement under acidic conditions to give a carbonyl compound via migration from a vicinal diol-like framework. Which statement best distinguishes pinacol vs semipinacol logic in predicting the migrating group?]]></text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Pinacol and semipinacol rearrangements proceed through cationic character created after leaving-group generation (often dehydration), and migratory aptitude reflects how well the migrating group supports positive charge development in the rearranging framework (commonly aryl or hydride shifts can be strongly favored depending on context). Radical stability is irrelevant here; “stronger C–O bond” is not the mechanistic driver; medium acidity enables ionization but does not eliminate substituent-controlled migratory preferences.]]></text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[In both, the migrating group is determined only by radical stability.]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[In both, the migrating group is the one that forms the strongest C–O bond in the product.]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Migration is governed by relative ability to stabilize the developing carbocationic character during the rearrangement step, often favoring groups that can better support positive charge development.]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Correct!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Migration is governed solely by the acidity of the medium, not substituent effects.]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text><![CDATA[A reaction sequence generates an]]></text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[A reaction sequence generates an intermediate that could be either an aryne (benzyne-type) or a Meisenheimer complex (SNAr). Which single diagnostic outcome most strongly supports an **aryne** pathway?]]></text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Aryne intermediates are highly strained and can be attacked at either aryne carbon; with unsymmetrical systems this often produces regioisomer mixtures governed by distortion/inductive effects rather than the strict EWG requirements of SNAr. SNAr is classically promoted by strong EWGs that stabilize the Meisenheimer intermediate; solvent effects described here align more with anionic intermediates; strong fixed para selectivity is not a hallmark of aryne chemistry.]]></text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Reaction proceeds only when a strong electron-withdrawing group is ortho/para to the leaving group.]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[A mixture of regioisomeric substitution products is obtained from an unsymmetrical aryl precursor and a single nucleophile.]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Correct!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[The reaction is accelerated by polar protic solvents due to stabilization of the Meisenheimer complex.]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[The reaction shows strong para selectivity regardless of substitution pattern.]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name>
      <text><![CDATA[A transformation could proceed via]]></text>
    </name>
    <questiontext format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[A transformation could proceed via (i) a singlet carbene pathway giving stereospecific cyclopropanation, or (ii) a triplet carbene pathway giving stepwise addition. Which product-level observation best supports a **triplet carbene** mechanism?]]></text>
    </questiontext>
    <defaultgrade>1.0000000</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0.3333333</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>1</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>ABCD</answernumbering>
    <generalfeedback format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Triplet carbenes commonly react stepwise through diradical character, which can scramble stereochemical information and reduce stereospecificity compared with singlet carbenes that often cyclopropanate alkenes in a concerted, stereospecific manner. Anti-Markovnikov HBr addition is a radical-chain halogenation topic, not carbene cyclopropanation; Meisenheimer complexes pertain to SNAr, not carbene pathways.
(https://ppl-ai-file-upload.s3.amazonaws.com/web/direct-files/collection_99e4096c-742b-4ed1-9fa1-79a24cd1a07e/e060820a-2d31-40e4-9eb3-489f8d4f9770/organic_unit_03.txt)
(https://ppl-ai-file-upload.s3.amazonaws.com/web/direct-files/collection_99e4096c-742b-4ed1-9fa1-79a24cd1a07e/00bf4220-38b7-4615-9d99-427b9a8f50a1/organic_unit_09.txt)
(https://ppl-ai-file-upload.s3.amazonaws.com/web/direct-files/collection_99e4096c-742b-4ed1-9fa1-79a24cd1a07e/26588078-225d-4384-895e-f69546b64bf1/inorganic_unit_03.txt)
(https://ppl-ai-file-upload.s3.amazonaws.com/web/direct-files/collection_99e4096c-742b-4ed1-9fa1-79a24cd1a07e/25698250-8500-4253-8ccc-ffa5a17ff53e/organic_unit_02.txt)
(https://ppl-ai-file-upload.s3.amazonaws.com/web/direct-files/collection_99e4096c-742b-4ed1-9fa1-79a24cd1a07e/f41187d8-4c1f-42a8-b69c-1b08ca48bd7f/organic_unit_04.txt)]]></text>
    </generalfeedback>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Complete retention of alkene stereochemistry in the cyclopropane product.]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="100" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Loss of stereospecificity (formation of products inconsistent with a single concerted addition geometry).]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Correct!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Exclusive formation of anti-Markovnikov addition product of HBr.]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html">
      <text><![CDATA[Formation of a Meisenheimer complex observed spectroscopically.]]></text>
      <feedback format="html">
        <text><![CDATA[Wrong!]]></text>
      </feedback>
    </answer>
  </question>
</quiz>
